"After reaching the shore"
"I love the sea."
"After the hair greys"
"I understand the world."
"Yesterday's joys come together"
"Today, at this moment,"
they find meaning."
"Today's joys will come together"
"To find their
meaning tomorrow."
"To live my life
that I never lived."
"Unable to bear this, upwards I go"
"To kindle my never ending passion."
"Here and now, I am coming out of it"
"Here and now,
I immerse into the depths"
"I look at myself
as someone else."
"Not with any reason,
just naturally."
"With clarity, like
that of a sunray!"
"I dont belong to these depths,
but I dwell in them."
"As a mirror I am born"
"I become everything I see."
"The joy of a kitten's
caress on my feet"
"Is a life enough for me."
"I want to stroke, everything I
come across, beautifully!"
"I will always be myself."
"Every day I will
live to the fullest"
"Will object, a life
of conventions."
"I will live a life
of supreme essence!!!"
"I will become as
pure as possible."
"With the wind flies the Hawk."
"Beautifully, without a path."
"It being its own reality."
"Like the rock that goes to
the depth of the waters"
"With a renouncing of sound"
"I drown in the sights I see."
"Like the bird that rides
on the bull's hump"
"I will live upon the Earth."
"I would join hands,
and walk along with the Earth."
"Some kind of ecstasy is flowing"
"That provides depth!!!"
"This moment envelops like a mother"
"Singing a lullaby"
"After reaching the shore"
"I love the sea."
"After the hair greys"
"I understand the world."
"Yesterday's joys come together"
"Today, at this moment
they find meaning."
"Today's joys will
come together"
"To find their meaning tomorrow."
(Priest's chants)
Come.
Come, all of you.
Good morning
Greetings.
Greetings sir.