October is inventory time.
So right now, Statler Toyota
is making the best deals of the year...
on all 1985-model Toyotas.
You won't find a better car
at a better price...
with better service
anywhere in Hill Valley.
That's Statler Toyota
in downtown Hill Valley.
But, hurry. This price is only good
through the end of the month.
The Senate is expected
to vote on this today.
In other news,
officials at the Pacific Nuclear
research facility have denied...
the rumor that a case of
missing plutonium was in fact...
stolen from their vault
two weeks ago.
A Libyan terrorist group had claimed
responsibility for the alleged theft.
However, officials now
attribute the discrepancy...
to a simple clerical error.
The FBI, which is
investigating the matter,
had no comment.
Hey, Doc?
Doc?
Hello! Anybody home?
Einstein, come here, boy.
What's going on?
Oh, God!
Oh, Jesus!
That is disgusting.
Where the hell is he?
Whoa!
Rock 'n' roll.
- Yo.
- Marty, is that you?
Hey, hey, Doc.
- Where are you?
- Thank God I've found you.
Listen, can you meet me
at Twin Pines Mall tonight at 1:15?
I made a major breakthrough,
and I need your assistance.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
1:15 in the morning?
- Yes.
- Doc, what's going on?
- Where you been all week?
- Working.
Where is Einstein?
Is he with you?
Yeah, he's right here.
You know Doc, you left
your equipment on all week.
My equipment?
That reminds me, Marty.
You better not hook up to the amplifier.
There's a slight possibility of overload.
Yeah.
- I'll keep that in mind.
- Good.
I'll see you tonight.
Don't forget now.
- 1:15 A.M., Twin Pines Mall.
- Right.
Are those my clocks I hear?
Yeah, it's 8 o'clock.
Perfect!
My experiment worked.
They're all exactly 25 minutes slow.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Doc.
Are you telling me that it's 8:25?
Precisely.
Damn!
I'm late for school.
♪ The power of love is a curious thing ♪
♪ Make a one man weep, ♪
♪ Make another man sing ♪
♪ Change a hawk to a little white dove ♪
♪ More than a feeling ♪
♪ That's the power of love ♪
♪ You don't need money ♪
♪ Don't take fame ♪
♪ Don't need no credit card ♪
♪ to ride this train ♪
♪ It's strong and it's sudden ♪
♪ And it's cruel sometimes ♪
♪ But it might just save your life ♪
♪ That's the power of love ♪
♪ Can you feel it ♪
Oh, Jennifer.
Marty don't go this way.
Strickland's looking for you.
If you get caught,
it'll be four tardies in a row.
Alright, come on.
I think we're safe.
You know this time
it wasn't my fault.
The doc set all his clocks
25 minutes slow.
The doc?
Am I to understand you're still hanging
around with Dr. Emmett Brown, McFly?
Tardy slip for you, Miss Parker.
And one for you, McFly.
I believe that makes four in a row.
Now, let me give you a nickel's worth
of free advice, young man.
This so-called Dr. Brown is dangerous.
He's a real nutcase.
You hang around with him,
you're gonna end up in big trouble.
Oh, yes, sir.
You got a real attitude problem, McFly.
You're a slacker.
You remind me of your father
when he went here.
He was a slacker, too.
Can I go now, Mr. Strickland?
I noticed your band is on the roster for
the dance auditions after school today.
Why even bother, McFly?
You don't have a chance.
You're too much like your old man.
No McFly ever amounted to anything
in the history of Hill Valley.
Yeah, well,
history is going to change.
Next, please.
Okay, let's rock 'n' roll.
Alright.
We're the...
We're the Pinheads.
One, two, three.
Okay, that's enough.
Thank you, fellas.
Hold it.
Hold it, fellas.
I'm afraid you're just too darn loud.
Next, please.
Where's the next group, please.
Re-elect Mayor Goldie Wilson.
Progress is his middle name.
"Too loud."
I can't believe it.
I'm never gonna get a chance
to play in front of anybody.
Marty, one rejection
isn't the end of the world.
Nah, I just don't think
I'm cut out for music.
But, you're good, Marty.
You're really good.
And this audition tape
of yours is great.
You've got to send it in
to the record company.
- It's like Doc's always saying.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
If you put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
That's good advice, Marty.
Alright, okay, Jennifer. What...
What if I send in the tape
and they don't like it?
I mean, what if they say
I'm no good?
What if they say: Get out of here, kid.
You got no future?
I mean I just don't think
I can take that kind of rejection.
Jesus! I'm starting
to sound like my old man.
Come on, Marty,
it's not that bad.
At least, he's letting you
borrow the car tomorrow night.
Check out that 4x4.
That is hot.
Okay, back her up.
Someday, Jennifer.
Someday.
Wouldn't it be great
to take that truck up to the lake?
Throw a couple of
sleeping bags in the back.
Lie out underneath the stars.
- Stop it.
- What?
Does your mom know?
About tomorrow night?
No, get out of town.
My mom thinks I'm going
camping with the guys.
Look Jennifer, my mother would freak out
if she knew I was going with you.
I'd get the standard lecture about...
how she never did that kind of stuff
when she was a kid.
I mean look...
I think the woman was born a nun.
She's just trying
to keep you respectable.
She's not doing a very good job.
Terrible.
Save the clock tower!
Save the clock tower.
Mayor Wilson is sponsoring
an initiative to replace that clock.
Thirty years ago,
lightning struck that clock tower
and the clock hasn't run since.
We at the Hill Valley
Preservation Society think
it should be preserved
exactly the way it is.
- As part of our history and heritage.
- Here you go lady. Here's a quarter.
Thanks you.
Don't forget to take a flyer.
- Alright.
- Save the clock tower!
Where were we?
- Right about here.
- Jennifer!
- It's my dad.
- Right.
I've got to go.
I'll call you tonight.
Uh, I'll be at my grandma's.
Here, let me give you the number.
Bye.
♪ That's the power of love ♪
♪ First time you feel it, ♪
♪ it might make you sad ♪
♪ Next time you feel it, ♪
♪ it might make you mad ♪
♪ But do be glad baby when you've found ♪
♪ That's the power
makes the world go 'round ♪
♪ And it don't take money ♪
♪ Don't take fame ♪
♪ Don't need no credit card ♪
♪ to ride this train ♪
♪ It's strong and it's sudden ♪
♪ It can be cruel sometimes ♪
♪ But it might just save your life ♪
License, California.
Bravo, Tango, Delta 6-2-9.
Tow for impoundment.
Any unit, please, respond.
Perfect.
Just perfect.
Listen, this isn't fun.
I can't believe,
you'd loan me your car,
without telling me it had a blind spot.
- Blind spot?
- I could've been killed.
Now, now, Biff, now,
I never noticed that the car had any
blind spot before when I would drive it.
Hi, son.
What, are you blind, McFly?
It's there. How else do you
explain that wreck out there?
Biff, um, can I, can I assume...
that your insurance is gonna
pay for the damage?
My insurance?
It's your car.
Your insurance should pay for.
I, I wanna know
who's gonna pay for this?
I spilled beer all over it
when that car smashed into me.
Who's gonna pay my cleaning bill?
- Ah!
- And where's my reports?
Uh, well, I haven't
finished those up yet.
But, you know I, I figured
since they weren't due 'til--
Hello?
Hello, anybody home?
Huh?
- Think, McFly.
- Alright.
Think!
I got to have time
to get them retyped.
Uh, you realize
what would happen
if I hand in my reports
in your handwriting?
I'll get fired.
You wouldn't want that
to happen, would you?
- Would you?
- Of course not, Biff.
No I wouldn't want that to happen.
Now look. I'll finish
those reports tonight...
and I'll run them on over
first thing tomorrow, alright?
Hey, not too early.
I sleep in Saturday.
Look. Why your shoe's untied.
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
Got the place fixed up nice,
though, McFly.
I have your car towed
all the way to your house,
and all you got for me is lite beer?
What are you looking at, butthead?
Say hi to your mom for me.
I know what you're gonna say, son.
And you're right.
You're right.
But, uh...
Biff just happens to be
my supervisor and I'm...
afraid I'm just not very good
at confrontations.
But the car, Dad.
I mean, he wrecked it.
He totaled it.
I needed that car tomorrow night, Dad.
You have any idea
how important this was to me?
You have any clue?
I know, and all I can say is, I'm...
I'm sorry.
Believe me, Marty.
You're better off without
having to worry about all the...
aggravation and headaches...
playing at that dance.
He's absolutely right, Marty.
The last thing you need
is headaches.
Kids?
We're gonna have to eat
this cake by ourselves.
Your Uncle Joey didn't make
parole again.
I think it would be nice
if you all dropped him a line.
Uncle Jailbird Joey?
- He's your brother, Mom.
- Yeah.
I think it's a major embarrassment,
having an uncle in prison.
We all make mistakes in life, children.
Goddamn it!
I'm late.
David, watch your mouth!
Come here and kiss your mother
before you go.
- Come here.
- Come on, Mom, make it fast.
I'll miss my bus.
See you later, Pop.
- Woo!
- What?
Time to change that oil.
Change that oil.
Hey, Marty.
I'm not your answering service.
While you were outside
pouting over the car,
Jennifer Parker called you twice.
I don't like her, Marty.
Any girl who calls up a boy
is just asking for trouble.
Oh, Mom, there is nothing wrong
with calling a boy.
I think it's terrible.
Girls chasing boys.
When I was your age,
I never chased a boy,
or called a boy, or...
sat in a parked car with a boy.
Then how am I ever supposed
to meet anybody?
Well, it'll just happen.
Like the way I met your father.
That was so stupid.
Grandpa hit him with the car.
It was meant to be.
Anyway.
If Grandpa hadn't hit him,
then none of you
would have been born.
Yeah, well.
I still don't understand what Dad
was doing in the middle of the street.
What was it, George?
Bird-watching?
What, Lorraine?
What?
Anyway, your Grandpa hit him
with the car...
and brought him into the house.
He seemed so helpless.
Like a little lost puppy.
- And my heart just went out to him.
- Yeah, Mom, we know.
You've told us this story
a million times.
You felt sorry for him.
So, you decided to go with him
to the Fish Under the Sea dance.
No, no. It was the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance.
Our first date.
I'll never forget it.
It was the night of that terrible
thunderstorm, remember George?
Your father kissed me for the very
first time on that dance floor.
And then, it was then
that I realized...
that I was gonna spend
the rest of my life with him.
Oh, no.
Hello.
Marty, you didn't fall asleep, did you?
No, uh, Doc.
Uh, no.
No, don't, don't be silly.
Listen, this is very important.
I forgot my video camera.
Can you stop by my place and
pick it up on your way to the mall?
Uh, yeah.
I'm, I'm on my way.
Einstein!
Hey, Einstein!
Where's the doc, boy?
Huh?
Doc!
Marty!
- You made it.
- Yeah.
Welcome to my latest experiment.
This is the big one, the one
I've been waiting for all my life.
Uh, well, it's a DeLorean, right?
Bear with me, Marty.
All your questions will be answered.
Roll tape and we'll proceed.
Uh, Doc?
Uh, is that a Devo suit?
Never mind that now,
never mind that now. Not now, not now.
Alright, I'm ready.
Good evening.
I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm standing on the parking lot
at Twin Pines Mall.
It's Saturday morning,
October 26, 1985, 1:18 a.m.
And this is temporal experiment
number one.
Come on, on, Einie.
Hey, hey, boy, get in there.
That a boy!
In there, you go.
Sit down.
Put your seatbelt on.
That's it.
Whoa, whoa!
Okay, okay.
Please note...
that Einstein's clock,
is in precise synchronization
with my control watch.
- Got it?
- Right. Check, Doc.
Good.
Have a good trip, Einstein.
Watch your head.
You got that thing
hooked up to the...
- car?
- Watch this.
Yeah. Okay.
Got it.
Jesus!
Not me!
The car. the car!
If my calculations are correct,
when this baby hits 88 miles per hour,
you're gonna see some serious shit.
Watch this, watch this!
What did I tell you?
88 miles per hour!
The temporal displacement occurred
exactly 1:20 a.m and 0 seconds!
Hot! Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ, Doc!
You just disintegrated Einstein.
Calm down, Marty.
I didn't disintegrate anything.
The molecular structure of both
Einstein and the car are completely intact.
Then where the hell are they?
The appropriate question is...
When the hell are they?
You see, Einstein has just become
the world's first time traveler.
I sent him into the future.
One minute into the future,
to be exact.
At precisely 1:21 a.m and 0 seconds,
we shall catch up with him
and the time machine.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Doc.
Uh...
Are you telling me,
you built a time machine...
out of a DeLorean?
The way I see it,
if you're going to build
a time machine into a car,
why not do it in some style?
Besides, the stainless-steel
construction made the flux dispersal...
Look out!
What? What?
Is it hot?
It's cold. Damn cold.
Einstein, you little devil!
Einstein's clock is exactly one minute
behind mine and still ticking!
- He's alright.
- He's fine.
And he's completely unaware
that anything happened.
As far as he's concerned,
the trip was instantaneous.
That's why his watch is exactly
one minute behind mine.
He skipped over that minute
to instantly arrive at this moment in time.
Come here.
- I'll show you how it works.
- Alright.
First,
you turn the time circuits on.
This readout tells you
where you're going.
This one tells you where you are.
This one tells you where you were.
You input your destination time
on this keypad.
Say you wanna see the signing
of the Declaration of Independence.
Or witness the birth of Christ.
Here's a red-letter date
in the history of science.
November 5, 1955.
Yes, of course.
Why? I don't get it.
What happened?
That was the day
I invented time travel.
I remember it vividly.
I was standing on the edge
of my toilet, hanging a clock.
The porcelain was wet, I slipped,
hit my head on the edge of the sink.
And when I came to,
I had a revelation.
A vision.
A picture in my head.
A picture of this.
This is what makes time travel possible.
The flux capacitor.
Flux capacitor?
It's taken almost 30 years
and my entire family fortune...
to realize the vision of that day.
My God, has it been that long?
Things have certainly changed
around here.
I remember when this was all farmland
as far as the eye could see.
Old man Peabody owned all of this.
He had this crazy idea...
about breeding pine trees.
This is, uh...
this is heavy-duty, Doc.
This is great.
Uh, does it run like on regular
unleaded gasoline?
Unfortunately, no.
It requires something
with a little more kick.
Plutonium.
Uh, plutonium.
Wait a minute. Are you...
are you telling me that
this sucker is nuclear?
Hey, hey, hey!
Keep rolling, keep rolling there.
No, no, no, no.
This sucker's electrical.
But, I need a nuclear reaction...
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts
of electricity I need.
Doc, you don't just walk
into a store and, and buy plutonium.
Did you rip that off?
Of course, from a group
of Libyan Nationalists.
They wanted me to build them a bomb.
So, I took their plutonium...
and in turn gave them a shoddy bomb
casing full of used pinball machine parts.
- Come on. Let's get you a radiation suit.
- Jesus!
We must prepare to reload.
It's safe now.
Everything's lead-lined.
Don't you lose those tapes now.
I need that as a record.
Let's put this back in here.
There we go.
Wait! Oh!
Almost forgot my luggage.
I mean, who knows if they got
cotton underwear in the future.
I'm allergic to all synthetics.
The future?
- That's where you're going.
- That's right.
25 years into the future.
I've always dreamed of seeing
the future, looking beyond my years,
seeing the progress of mankind.
Why not?
I'll also be able to see who wins
the next 25 World Series.
- Uh, Doc?
- Huh?
Uh, look me up
when you get there.
Indeed I will.
Roll them.
I...
Dr. Emmett Brown...
am about to embark
on an historic journey.
What am I thinking of?
I almost forgot to bring
extra plutonium.
How do I ever expect to get back?
One pellet, one trip.
I must be out of my mind.
What is it, Einie?
Oh, my God!
They found me. I don't know how,
but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Who? Who?
Who do you think?
The Libyans!
Over there!
Over there.
Holy shit!
I'll draw their fire!
Doc, wait!
No!
You bastard!
Go!
Damn Soviet gun.
Come on, move!
Uh, damn it!
Jesus!
Holy shit!
Let's see if you bastards can do 90.
What, what is it?
W-What is it, Pa?
Looks like an airplane.
Without wings.
That ain't no airplane.
Look.
Don't look!
Listen! Oh!
Hello.
Uh.
Excuse me.
Sorry about your barn.
It's already mutated
into the human form.
Shoot it!
Take that,
you mutated son of a bitch!
Wait!
Oh, we will, oh!
My pine!
Why you...
You space bastard!
You killed our pine!
You're fine, you're fine.
Okay, McFly.
Get a grip on yourself.
It's all a dream.
It's just a very intense dream.
Whoa, whoa.
- Listen, you got to help me.
- Don't stop, Wilbur! Don't!
It can't be.
This is nuts.
Come on.
Perfect.
♪ Mr. Sandman ♪
♪ Bring me a dream ♪
♪ Make her complexion ♪
♪ Like peaches and cream ♪
♪ Give her two lips ♪
♪ Like roses and clover ♪
♪ Then tell me that ♪
♪ my lonesome nights are over ♪
♪ Sandman ♪
♪ I'm so alone ♪
♪ Don't have nobody to call my own ♪
♪ Please, turn on your magic beam ♪
♪ Mr. Sandman, bring me a dream ♪
♪ Make her the cutest that I've ever seen ♪
Remember, fellow citizens,
the future is in your hands.
If you believe in progress,
re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
Progress is his middle name.
Mayor Red Thomas'
progress platform,
means more jobs,
better education,
bigger civic improvements,
and lower taxes.
On election day,
cast your vote for a proven leader.
Re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
This has got to be a dream.
Hey, kid.
What you do?
Jump ship?
What?
What's with the life preserver?
I just want to use the phone.
Yeah, it's in the back.
Brown.
Great.
You're alive.
Come on.
- Do you know where 1640 Riverside...
- You gonna order something, kid?
Uh, yeah.
Give me, give me a tab.
Tab? I can't give you a tab
unless you order something.
Right.
Give me a Pepsi Free.
You want a Pepsi, pal,
you're gonna pay for it.
Well, just give me something
without any sugar in it, okay?
Something without sugar.
Hey, McFly.
What do you think you're doing?
Biff.
Hey, I'm talking to you McFly,
you Irish bug!
Oh, hey, Biff. Hey, guys.
How are you doing?
You got my homework finished, McFly?
Uh, well actually, I figured,
since it wasn't due 'til Monday--
Hello? Hello?
Anybody home?
Hey, think, McFly. Think.
I got to have time to recopy it.
You realize what would happen if
I hand in my homework in your handwriting?
I'll get kicked out of school.
You wouldn't want that to happen,
would you?
- Would you?
- Now, of course not, Biff.
- No, no.
- I wouldn't want that to happen.
What are you looking at, butthead?
Hey, Biff, get a load of
this guy's life preserver.
- Dork thinks he's gonna drown.
- Yeah.
Yeah, well, how about
my homework, McFly?
Uh, okay, Biff.
Well, I'll, uh...
I'll finish that one up tonight...
and then I'll bring it over
first thing tomorrow morning.
Hey, not too early.
I sleep in Sunday.
Oh McFly, your shoe's untied!
Oh, ah, ah!
- Don't be so gullible, McFly.
- Okay.
- I don't want to see you in here again.
Alright. Bye-bye.
What?
You're George McFly!
Yeah. And who are you?
Say! Why do you let those boys
push you around like that for?
Well, they're bigger than me.
Stand tall, boy.
Have some respect for yourself.
Don't you know,
if you let people walk over you now,
they'll be walking over you
for the rest of your life.
Look at me.
You think I'm gonna spend
the rest of my life in this slop house?
- Watch it, Goldie.
- No, sir.
I'm gonna make something of myself.
I'm going to night school.
And one day,
I'm going to be somebody.
That's right.
He's going to be mayor.
Yeah, I'm...
Mayor!
Now, that's a good idea.
I could run for mayor.
A colored mayor.
That'll be the day.
You wait and see, Mr. Caruthers.
I will be mayor.
I'll be the most powerful man
in Hill Valley.
And I'm going to clean up this town.
Good. You can start
by sweeping the floor.
Mayor Goldie Wilson.
I like the sound of that.
Hey, Dad!
George!
Hey, you on the bike!
He's a peeping Tom.
Dad!
Hey, wait.
Wait a minute.
Who are you?
Stella!
Another one of these damn kids
jumped in front of my car!
Come on out here!
Help me take him in the house!
Mom?
That you?
There, there, now.
Just relax.
You've been asleep
for almost nine hours now.
Yeah.
I had a horrible nightmare.
I dreamed that I went...
back in time.
It was terrible.
Well...
you're safe and sound now,
back in good old 1955.
1955?
You're my mo--
My name is Lorraine.
Lorraine Baines?
Yeah.
But, you're--
You're so uh...
You're so...
Thin!
Just relax, Calvin.
You got a big bruise on your head.
Ah!
Where are my pants?
Over there.
On my hope chest.
I've never seen
purple underwear before, Calvin.
Calvin? Why, why you keep
calling me Calvin?
That is your name, isn't it?
Calvin Klein?
It's written all over your underwear.
Oh, I guess they call you Cal?
No, actually, people...
call me Marty.
Oh.
Pleased to meet you, Calvin.
Marty.
Klein.
Do you mind if I sit here?
No. Fine.
No. Good. Fine.
Good.
That's, uh, a big bruise
you have there.
- Oh!
- Lorraine, are you up there?
Oh, my God!
It's my mother.
Quick.
Put your pants back on.
So, tell me, Marty,
how long have you been in port?
- Excuse me?
- I guessed you're a sailor, aren't you?
That's why you wear
that life preserver.
Uh, coast guard.
Sam?
Here's the young man you hit
with your car out there.
He's alright.
Thank God.
What were you doing in the middle
of the street, a kid your age?
Don't pay attention to him.
He's in one of his moods.
Sam, you quit fiddling with that thing.
Come in here to dinner.
Now, let's see.
You already know Lorraine.
This is Milton.
This is Sally.
That's Toby.
And over there in the playpen
is little baby, Joey.
So, you're my uncle Joey.
Better get used to these bars, kid.
Yes, Joey just loves
being in his playpen.
He cries whenever we take him out,
so we just leave him in there all the time.
Well, Marty,
I hope you like meatloaf.
Well, listen,
I really ought to--
Sit here, Marty.
Sam, stop fiddling with that thing
and come in here and eat your dinner.
Oh oh oh!
Look at it roll.
Now we can watch
Jackie Gleason while we eat.
Our first television set.
Dad just picked it up today.
Do you have a television?
Well, yeah.
You know, we have...
two of them.
Wow!
You must be rich.
Oh, honey, he's teasing you.
Nobody has two television sets.
Mm.
Hey.
Hey, I've seen this one.
I've seen this one, it's a classic.
This is where Ralph dresses up
as a man from space.
What do you mean, you've seen this?
It's brand-new.
Yeah, well, I saw it on a rerun.
What's a rerun?
You'll find out.
You know, Marty,
you look so familiar to me.
Do I know your mother?
Yeah, I think, maybe, you do.
Oh, then, I want to give her a call.
I don't want her to worry about you.
You can't.
Uh, that is,
uh, nobody, uh...
nobody's home.
Oh.
Yet.
Uh, listen.
You, you know where
Riverside Drive is?
It's on the other end of town,
a block past Maple.
East end of town.
Wait a minute,
a block past Maple.
That's, that's John F. Kennedy Drive.
Who the hell is John F. Kennedy?
Um, mother? Uh...
With Marty's parents out of town,
don't you think
he ought to spend the night?
I mean after all,
Dad almost killed him with the car.
That's true, Marty.
I think maybe you should spend the night.
I think you're our responsibility.
Well, gee, I don't know.
And he can sleep in my room.
I gotta go!
Uh, I gotta go.
Thanks very much, it was wonderful.
You're all great.
Uh, see you all later.
Too much later.
He's a very strange young man.
He's an idiot.
Comes from upbringing.
His parents are probably idiots, too.
Lorraine, you ever have a kid
who acts that way, I'll disown you.
Doc?
Don't say a word.
- Doc.
- I don't wanna know your name.
I don't want to know
anything bout you.
- Listen, Doc.
- Quiet!
- Doc, doc, it's me, Marty.
- Don't tell me anything.
- Doc, you got to help--
- Quiet! Quiet.
I'm gonna read your thoughts.
Let's see now.
You've come here from a great distance?
- Yeah. Exactly.
- Now, don't tell me!
Uh, you want me to buy a subscription
to the Saturday Evening Post.
- No.
- Not a word.
Not a word.
Not a word now!
Quiet.
Uh.
Toys.
You want me to make a donation...
to the Coast Guard Youth Auxiliary.
Doc.
I'm from the future.
I came here in a time machine
that you invented.
Now, I need your help
to get back to the year 1985.
My God.
Do you know what this means?
It means that this damn thing
doesn't work at all!
- Shit! Fuck!
- Doc, you got to help me.
You are the only one who knows
how your time machine works.
Time machine?
I haven't invented any time machine.
Okay. Alright.
I'll prove it to you.
Look at my driver's license.
Expires 1987?
Look at my birthday,
for crying out loud!
I haven't even been born yet.
And look at this picture.
My brother, my sister, and me.
Look at her sweatshirt, Doc.
Class of 1984?
Pretty mediocre photographic fakery.
They cut off your brother's hair.
I'm telling the truth, Doc.
You got to believe me.
Then tell me...
future boy.
Who's President of
the United States in 1985?
Ronald Reagan.
Ronald Reagan?
The actor?
Then who's vice president?
Jerry Lewis?
I suppose Jane Wyman...
- is the First Lady.
- Whoa, wait, Doc!
And Jack Benny is
secretary of the treasury.
- Ha!
- Doc, you gotta listen to me.
I've had enough practical
jokes for one evening.
Good night, future boy!
No, wait, Doc.
Doc.
The, the bruise, the bruise on your head.
I know how that happened.
You told me the whole story.
You were standing on your toilet,
and you were hanging a clock,
and you fell,
and you hit your head on the sink.
That's when you came up with
the idea for the flux capacitor,
which is what makes
time travel possible.
There's something wrong
with the starter.
So, I hid it...
here.
After I fell off my toilet,
I drew this.
The flux capacitor.
It works!
I finally invent something that works!
You bet your ass it works.
Somehow, we've got to sneak this
back to my laboratory.
We've got to get you home.
Okay, Doc, this is it.
Never mind that.
Never mind that now.
- Never mind that, you're fine.
- Why, that's me!
Look at me!
I'm an old man.
Good evening.
I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
I'm standing on the...
- parking lot at Twin Pines Mall.
- Thank God, I've still got my hair.
And what's on Earth
is this thing I'm wearing?
Why, this, this is a radiation suit.
Radiation suit?
Of course.
Because of all the fallout
from the atomic wars.
This...
is truly amazing.
A portable television studio.
No wonder your president
has to be an actor.
He's gotta look good on television.
Whoa, this is it.
This is the part coming up, Doc.
No, no, no, no.
This sucker's electrical.
But, I need a nuclear reaction
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts--
What did I just say?
This sucker's electrical.
but I need a nuclear reaction
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts--
- of electricity I need.
- 1.21 gigawatts!
1.21 gigawatts.
Great Scott!
What?
What the hell is a gigawatt?
How could I have been so careless?
1.21 gigawatts!
Tom, how am I going
to generate that kind of power?
It can't be done, can it?
Doc, look.
All we need is a little plutonium.
Oh, I'm sure that in 1985,
plutonium is available
in every corner drugstore.
but in 1955,
it's a little hard to come by.
Marty, I'm sorry,
but I'm afraid you're stuck here.
Whoa, whoa, Doc.
Stuck here?
I can't, I can't be stuck here.
I got a life in, in 1985.
I got a girl.
Is she pretty?
Doc, she's beautiful. She...
she's crazy about me.
Look at this.
Look what she wrote here, Doc.
I mean, that says it all.
Doc...
you're my only hope.
Marty, I'm sorry.
But, the only power source
capable of generating...
1.21 gigawatts of electricity
is a bolt of lightning.
- What did you say?
- A bolt of lightning.
Unfortunately, you never know
when or where it's ever gonna strike.
We do now.
This is it!
This is the answer.
It says here,
that a bolt of lightning is gonna
strike the clock tower
at precisely 10:04 p.m
next Saturday night.
If we could, somehow,
harness this lightning,
channel it...
into the flux capacitor,
it just might work.
Next Saturday night,
we're sending you back to the future!
Okay, alright.
Saturday's good.
I can spend a week in 1955.
We can hang out.
You can show me around.
Marty, that is completely
out of the question.
You must not leave this house.
You must not see anybody
or talk to anybody.
Anything you do can have serious
repercussions on future events.
Do you understand?
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
Marty?
You interacted with
anybody else today, besides me?
I, um...
Yeah, well, I might have
sort of bumped in to my parents.
Great Scott!
Let me see that photograph again
of your brother.
Uh.
Just as I thought.
This proves my theory.
Look at your brother.
His head's gone.
It's like, it's like it's been erased.
Erased from existence.
Whoa!
They really cleaned this place up.
Looks brand-new.
Now, remember.
According to my theory,
you interfered with
your parents' first meeting.
They don't meet,
they won't fall in love,
they won't get married,
and they won't have kids.
That's why your older brother's
disappearing from that photograph.
Your sister will follow,
and unless you repair the damage,
you'll be next.
- Sounds pretty heavy.
- Weight has nothing to do with it.
Which one's your pop?
That's him.
Okay, okay, you guys.
Oh, ha ha ha!
Very funny.
You guys are being real mature.
Maybe, you were adopted.
Okay, real mature, guys.
Okay, please.
Will you pick up my books?
- McFly.
- Look, that's Strickland.
Jesus!
Didn't that guy ever have hair?
Shape up, man.
You're a slacker.
Do you want to be a slacker
for the rest of your life?
No.
What did your mother
ever see in that kid?
I don't know, Doc.
Come on.
I, I guess she felt sorry for him
because her dad hit him with the car.
Hit me with the car.
That's the Florence Nightingale effect.
It happens in hospitals when
nurses fall in love with their patients.
Go to it, kid.
Hey, George.
Buddy.
I have been looking all over for you.
You remember me, the guy who
saved your life the other day?
- Oh. Yeah.
- Good.
There's somebody
I'd like you to meet.
Lorraine?
Calvin!
I'd like you to meet my good friend,
George McFly.
Hi.
It's really a pleasure to meet you.
- How's your head?
- Good. Fine.
Oh, I've been so worried about you
ever since you ran off the other night.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Come on, the party.
- I'm sorry, I have to go.
Come on!
Isn't he a dreamboat?
Doc, she didn't even look at him.
This is more serious than I thought.
Apparently, your mother is
amorously infatuated with you,
instead of your father.
Whoa! Wait, wait a minute, Doc.
Are you trying to tell me
that my mother...
has got the hots for me?
Precisely.
Whoa, this is heavy.
There's that word again, "Heavy".
Why are things so heavy in the future?
Is there a problem with
the Earth's gravitational pull?
- What?
- The only way...
we're gonna get those two to successfully
mate is if they're alone together.
So, you've got to get your father
and mother to interact.
Some sort of social--
Well, what?
You mean like a date?
- Right!
- What kind of date?
I don't know.
What do kids do in the '50s?
What? They're your parents.
You must know them.
What are their common interests?
What do they like to do together?
Nothing.
Look!
There's a rhythmic
ceremonial ritual coming up.
Of course, the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance!
They're supposed to go to this.
That's where they kiss for the first time.
Alright, kid.
You stick to your father like glue,
and make sure
he takes her to that dance.
George, buddy.
Remember that girl
I introduced you to?
Lorraine?
What are you writing?
Uh.
Stories.
Science fiction stories about...
visitors,
coming down to Earth,
from other planets.
Get out of town!
I didn't know
you did anything creative.
Well, let me read some.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I never, I never let
anybody read my stories.
Why not?
Well, what if they didn't like them?
What if they told me I was no good?
I guess that would be pretty hard
for somebody to understand.
Uh, no.
No, not hard at all.
So anyway, George.
About Lorraine.
She really likes you.
She told me to tell you
that she wants you to ask her...
to the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
All you got to do
is go over there and ask her.
What? Right here,
right now in the cafeteria?
What if she said no?
I don't know if I could take
that kind of a rejection.
Besides,
I think she'd rather go
with somebody else.
Uh, who?
Biff.
Don't kid around.
Come on.
- I'm gonna leave.
- What? You want it.
You know you want it.
You know you want me
to give it to you.
Shut your filthy mouth.
I'm not that kind of girl.
Oh, woo, woo!
Maybe, you are.
You just don't know it yet.
Get your meat hooks off of me.
You heard her.
She said, get your meat hooks...
off.
Uh, please.
So, what's it to you, butthead?
You know,
you've been looking for a fight.
- Alright!
- Fight!
Quiet!
Since you're new here,
I'm gonna cut you a break,
today.
So, why don't you make like a tree,
and get out of here.
George!
Why do you keep following me around?
Look, George.
I'm telling you, George.
If you do not ask Lorraine
to that dance,
I'm gonna regret it
for the rest of my life.
But, I can't go to the dance.
I'll miss my favorite television program,
Science Fiction Theatre.
Yeah, but, George...
Lorraine wants to go with you.
Give her a break.
Look, I'm just not ready,
to ask Lorraine out to the dance.
And not you...
or anybody else on this planet
is gonna make me change my mind.
Science Fiction Theatre.
Who are you?
Silence, Earthling.
My name is Darth Vader.
I am an extraterrestrial
from the planet Vulcan.
Marty!
Watch out!
Hey!
Marty!
- Marty.
- Hey, George, buddy.
You weren't at school.
What've you been doing all day?
I overslept.
Look, I need your help.
I have to ask Lorraine out,
but I don't know how to do it.
Alright. Okay, listen, keep your pants on.
She's over in the cafe.
God!
How do you--?
What made you
change your mind, George?
Last night,
Darth Vader came down...
from Planet Vulcan and told me that
if I didn't take Lorraine out,
that he'd melt my brain.
Yeah, well, uh, let's,
let's just keep this...
brain melting stuff
to ourselves, okay?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Alright, okay.
Alright.
There she is, George.
Now, just go in there and invite her.
Okay. But,
I don't know what to say.
Just say anything, George.
Say whatever's natural,
or the first thing
that comes into your mind.
Nothing's coming to my mind.
Jesus, George!
It's a wonder I was even born.
- What? What?
- Nothing, nothing.
Nothing.
Look.
Tell her destiny...
brought you together.
Tell her that she is
the most beautiful girl...
you've ever seen in the world.
Girls like that stuff.
What are you doing, George?
I'm writing this down.
This is good stuff.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Oh.
- Let's go.
- Can you take care of that?
- Alright.
Lou?
Give me a milk.
Chocolate.
Lorraine.
My density...
has popped me to you.
What?
Oh.
What I meant to say...
- was...
- Wait a minute.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
Yes.
Yes. I'm George.
George McFly.
I'm your density.
I mean...
your destiny.
Oh.
Hey, McFly.
Geez!
I thought I told you
never to come in here.
Well, it's gonna cost you.
How much money you got on you?
Well...
How much do you want, Biff?
Whoa!
Alright, punk.
- Now, I'm gonna--
- Whoa, whoa, Biff.
What's that?
Calvin Klein.
Oh, my God!
He's a dream.
Whoa, whoa!
Kid, kid! Stop, stop!
- Stop, stop.
- Hey!
- Let me borrow it.
- Stop, stop, stop!
- I'll get it back to you, alright?
- Come on, go, go!
You broke it.
Come back here!
Wow, look at him go!
Damn it!
To the car, to the car!
Go, go!
What's that thing he's on?
It's a board with wheels.
He's an absolute dream.
Come on, come on, come on!
Look out for the car!
I'm gonna ram him.
Shit!
Thanks a lot, kid.
I'm gonna get
that son of a bitch.
Where does he come from?
Yeah, where does he live?
I don't know.
But, I'm gonna find out.
Oh, my God.
They found me.
I don't know how,
but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Oh, my God.
They found me.
I don't know how,
but they found me.
Run for it, Marty!
Doc?
Oh, hi, Marty.
I didn't hear you come in.
Fascinating device, this...
video unit.
Listen, Doc.
You know, there's something
I haven't told you about the night
- we made that tape.
- Please, Marty, don't tell me.
No man should know too much
about his own destiny.
- You don't understand.
- I do understand.
If I know too much
about my own future,
I can endanger my own existence.
Just as you have endangered yours.
You, you're right.
Now, let me show you my plan
for sending you home.
Please, excuse the crudity of this model.
I didn't have time to build it
to scale or to paint it.
- It's good.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Okay, now.
We run some industrial strength
electrical cable from the top...
of the clock tower, down...
suspending it over the street
between these two lamp posts.
Meanwhile, we've outfitted...
the time vehicle with
this big pole and hook,
which runs directly
into the flux capacitor.
At the calculated moment,
you start off,
from down the street,
driving directly toward the cable,
accelerating to 88 miles per hour.
According to the flyer,
at precisely 10:04 p.m,
this Saturday night,
lightning will strike the clock tower,
electrifying the cable,
just as the connecting hook makes contact,
thereby, sending 1.21 gigawatts
into the flux capacitor,
and sending you back to 1985.
Alright, now.
Watch this.
You wind up the car and release it.
I'll simulate the lightning.
Ready.
Set.
Release.
Whoa!
You're instilling me
with a lot of confidence, Doc.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of the lightning.
You take care of your pop.
By the way,
what happened today?
Did he ask her out?
I think so.
What did she say?
It's your mom!
She's tracked you down.
Quick.
Let's cover the time machine.
Hi,
Cal--
Marty.
Mom.
Lorraine.
Uh...
How did you know I was here?
I followed you.
Oh, uh, this is my doc.
My uncle.
Doc Brown.
- Hi.
Marty, listen.
This may seem a little forward,
but I was kind of wondering if you...
if, if you'd ask me to the...
Enchantment Under the Sea dance
on Saturday.
Uh, you mean...
you mean nobody's asked you?
No.
Not yet.
What about, what about George?
George McFly?
Oh.
He's kind of cute and all.
But, not--
Well,
I think a man should be strong.
So, he can stand up for himself,
and protect the woman he loves.
Don't you?
Yeah.
I still don't understand.
How am I supposed to go
to the dance with her,
if she's already going
to the dance with you?
Well, because George,
she wants to go with you.
She just doesn't know it yet.
That's why we got to show her that you,
George McFly, are a fighter.
You're somebody who's gonna
stand up for yourself,
somebody who's gonna protect her.
Yeah, but, I've never picked
a fight in my entire life.
Look, you're not gonna
be picking a fight, Dad.
Dad, dad, daddy-o.
You're coming to her rescue, right?
Okay, let's go over the plan again.
8:55, where are you gonna be?
I'm gonna be at the dance.
Right, and where am I gonna be?
You're gonna be in the car with her.
Right, okay.
So, right around 9:00,
she's gonna get very angry with me.
Why is she gonna
get angry with you?
Well, because George,
nice girls get angry...
when guys take advantage of them.
Oh.
You mean you're gonna
go touch her on her--
No, no, George.
Look.
It's just an act, right?
Okay. So, 9 o'clock,
you're strolling
through the parking lot.
You see us, uh,
struggling in the car.
You walk up,
you open the door and you say...
Your line, George.
Oh, uh...
Hey, you, get your damn hands off her!
You really think I ought to swear?
Yes, definitely.
God damn it, George, swear.
Okay. So now,
you come up.
You punch me in the stomach.
I'm out for the count, right?
And you and Lorraine live
happily ever after.
Well, you make it sound so easy.
I just,
I wish I wasn't so scared.
George, there's nothing to be scared of.
All it takes is a little self-confidence.
You know,
if you put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
Hill Valley area weather
this Saturday night.
Mostly clear,
with some scattered clouds.
Lows tonight in the upper 40s.
Are you sure about this storm?
Since when can weathermen
predict the weather?
Let alone the future.
You know, Marty, I'm gonna
be very sad to see you go.
You've really made
a difference in my life.
You've given me
something to shoot for.
Just knowing...
that I'm gonna be around to see 1985,
that I'm gonna succeed in this,
that I'm gonna have a chance
to travel through time,
It's gonna be really hard waiting
30 years before I can talk to you
about everything that's happened
in the past few days.
I'm really gonna miss you, Marty.
I'm really going to miss you.
Doc, about the future...
No!
Marty!
We've already agreed...
that having information about
the future can be extremely dangerous.
Even if your intentions are good,
it can backfire drastically.
Whatever you've got to tell me,
I'll find out through
the natural course of time.
Dear Dr. Brown.
On the night that I go back in time,
you will be...
shot by terrorists.
Please, take whatever
precautions necessary...
to prevent this terrible disaster.
Your friend,
Marty.
Evening, Dr. Brown.
What's with the wire?
Oh, just...
a little weather experiment.
What you got under here?
No, no, don't touch that!
Some new specialized
weather sensing equipment.
Yeah, well,
you got a permit for that?
Of course, I do.
Just a second.
Let me see if I can find it here.
Do you mind if we...
park...
for a while?
That's a great idea.
I'd love to park.
Huh?
Marty, I'm almost 18 years old.
It's not like I've never parked before.
What?
Marty, you seem so nervous.
Is something wrong?
No.
Lorraine, Lorraine,
what are you doing?
I swiped it from
the old lady's liquor cabinet.
Yeah, well,
you shouldn't drink.
- Why not?
- Because you...
you might regret it,
later in life.
Marty, don't be such a square.
Everybody who's anybody drinks.
Jeez, you smoke, too?
Marty, you're beginning
to sound just like my mother.
We're gonna take a little break,
but we'll be back in a while.
So, uh, don't nobody go nowhere.
Marty?
Why are you so nervous?
Lorraine.
Have you ever...
uh...
been in a situation where you knew
you had to act a certain way,
but when you got there,
you didn't know if
you could go through with it?
Oh, you mean like how you're
supposed to act on a first date?
Oh, uh, sort of.
Oh, I, I think, I know
exactly what you mean.
You, you, you do?
You know what I do
in those situations?
What?
I don't worry.
This is all wrong.
I don't, I don't know what it is.
But when I kiss you,
it's like I'm kissing...
my brother.
I guess that doesn't
make any sense, does it?
Believe me.
It makes perfect sense.
Biff's coming.
You caused 300 bucks damage
to my car you son of a bitch.
And I'm gonna
take it out of your ass.
Hold him.
Let him go, Biff.
You're drunk.
Well, look at what we have here.
No, no!
You're sitting right here with me.
- Come on, Lorraine.
- Let me go.
Leave her alone, you bastard!
Guys, take him in back, alright?
I'll be right there.
Just admit that you want it.
Come on.
Well, go on.
This ain't no peep show.
- Oh!
- Oh.
No! Stop!
Ouch!
Hey, let's put him in there.
Yeah.
That's for messing up my hair.
What the hell
are you doing to my car?
Hey, beat it, spook.
This don't concern you.
Who you calling spook, peckerwood?
Hey, hey, listen guys.
Look, I don't want to mess
with no reefer addicts, okay?
- Get home to your mama, boy.
- Biff!
Hurry, Biff!
Let me out of here!
Yo!
Reginald, where are your keys?
The keys are in the trunk.
Say that again?
I said, the keys are in here.
Come on!
Hey, you!
Get your damn hands off--
Uh, oh.
I think you got the wrong car, McFly.
George, help me!
Please!
Just turn around, McFly,
and walk away.
Please, George.
Are you deaf, McFly?
Close the door and beat it.
No, Biff.
You leave her alone.
Alright, McFly.
You're asking for it,
and now you're going to get it.
Biff, stop it!
Biff, you'll break his arm.
Biff, no!
Give me a hand here, Reginald.
Ouch!
Damn it, man!
I sliced my hand!
- Whose are these?
- Mine.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
You're going to break his arm!
Biff!
Biff, leave him alone!
Let him go!
Are you okay?
Who is that guy?
That's George McFly.
That's George McFly?
Excuse me.
The storm.
Hey, guys, you gotta get back
in there and finish the dance.
Hey, man.
Look at Marvin's hand.
He can't play with his hand like that,
and we can't play without him.
Yeah, well, look, Marvin.
Marvin, you got to play.
See, that's where they kiss
for the first time on the dance floor.
And if there is no music,
they can't dance.
If they can't dance,
they can't kiss.
If they can't kiss,
they can't fall in love and I'm history.
Hey man, the dance is over.
Unless that you know somebody else
that can play the guitar.
This is for all you lovers out there.
♪ Earth angel, Earth angel ♪
♪ Will you be mine? ♪
♪ My darling dear ♪
♪ Love you... ♪
George, aren't you gonna kiss me?
Uh, I don't know.
Scram, McFly.
I'm cutting in.
♪ Earth angel, Earth angel ♪
♪ The one I adore ♪
Hey, boy, you alright?
I can't play.
George!
George.
Excuse me.
♪ The vision of your happiness. ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Earth angel, Earth angel ♪
♪ Please, be mine. ♪
♪ My darling dear ♪
♪ Love you for all time. ♪
♪ I'm just a fool ♪
♪ A fool in love ♪
♪ With you. ♪
Yeah, yeah!
Man, that was good.
Let's do another one.
Uh, no, I got to go.
Come on, man.
Let's do something that really cooks.
Something that, that, that cooks.
Alright.
Alright. Uh...
Alright, this is, uh,
this is an oldie.
But, uh...
Well,
it's an oldie where I come from.
Alright, guys.
Sound, Mr. Blues riff in B.
Watch me for the changes,
and try and keep up, okay?
♪ Way down in Louisiana ♪
♪ Down to New Orleans ♪
♪ Way back up in the woods ♪
♪ Among the evergreens ♪
♪ There stood a log cabin ♪
♪ Made of earth and wood ♪
♪ Where lived a country boy ♪
♪ Named Johnny B. Goode ♪
♪ Who never ever learned ♪
♪ To read or write so well ♪
♪ But he could play a guitar ♪
♪ Just like he's ringing a bell ♪
♪ Go go ♪
♪ Go Johnny go go ♪
Hey, George, I heard you laid out Biff.
Nice going.
George, you ever think of
running for class president?
♪ Go Johnny go go ♪
♪ Johnny B. Goode ♪
Chuck! Chuck!
It's Marvin.
Your cousin, Marvin Berry.
You know that new sound
you're looking for?
Well, listen to this.
I guess, I guess you guys
aren't ready for that yet.
But, your kids are gonna love it.
Lorraine.
Marty, that was very interesting music.
Au, yeah.
Oh, and I hope you don't mind,
but George asked
if he could take me home.
Great! Good!
Good, Lorraine.
I had a feeling about you two.
I have a feeling, too.
Listen, I got to go,
but, uh, I wanted to
tell you that it's been...
educational.
Marty, will we ever see you again?
I guarantee it.
Well, Marty.
I want to thank you
for all your good advice. So...
I'll never forget it.
Right, George.
Well, uh...
good luck you guys.
Oh.
One other thing.
If you guys ever have kids,
and one of them,
when he's eight years old,
accidentally sets fire
to the living room rug,
go easy on him.
Okay.
Marty?
Such a nice name.
Damn!
Where is that kid?
Damn! Damn!
You're late!
You have no concept of time?
Hey, come on.
I had to change.
Do you think I'm going back
in that, that zoot suit?
Yeah, the old man
really came through.
- It worked.
- What?
He laid out Biff in one punch.
I didn't know he had it in him.
He's never stood up to Biff in his life.
Ever?
No. Why?
What's the matter?
Alright!
Let's set your destination time.
This is the exact time you left.
Let's send you back
at exactly the same time.
It'll be like you never left.
Now,
I painted a white line
on the street way over there.
That's where you'll start from.
I've calculated the precise distance,
taking into account
the acceleration speed,
and wind resistance retroactive
from the moment...
the lightning strikes,
which will be...
in exactly 7 minutes and 22 seconds.
When this alarm goes off,
you hit the gas.
Right.
Well,
I guess that's everything.
Thanks.
Thank you.
See you in about 30 years.
I hope so.
Don't worry!
As long as you hit that wire...
with the connecting hook
at precisely 88 miles an hour,
the instant the lightning
strikes the tower...
everything will be fine.
Right.
What's the meaning of this?
You'll find out in 30 years.
It's about the future, isn't it?
- It's information about the future.
- Wait a minute.
I warned you about this, kid.
The consequences could be disastrous!
Doc, that's a risk you're
going to have to take.
Your life depends on it!
No!
I refuse to accept the responsibility.
In that case,
I'll tell you straight out.
Great Scott!
You get the cable.
- I'll throw the rope down to you.
- Right.
I got it!
Doc!
Come on, come on.
Let's go!
Alright!
Take it up!
Go!
Doc!
What?
I have to tell you about the future.
- What?
- I have to tell you about the future!
What?
On the night,
I go back in time,
you get...
Whoa, whoa.
Oh.
Doc!
Oh!
Go!
No, Doc!
Look at the time!
You've got less than four minutes.
Please, hurry!
Yeah!
Mm!
Damn it, Doc!
Why did you have
to tear up that letter?
If I only had more time.
Wait a minute.
I got all the time I want.
I got a time machine.
I can just go back early
and warn him.
Okay.
Ten minutes ought to do it.
Time circuit's on.
Flux capacitor,
fluxing.
Engine running.
Alright.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
Not this time.
Come on, come on.
Oh.
Come on.
Here we go, here we go.
This time, come on.
Please. Please!
Come on!
Oh!
Doc.
Crazy drunk driver.
Woo!
Alright.
Fred.
You look great.
Everything looks great.
Oh, no.
1:24.
I still got time.
I'm coming, Doc!
No!
No, not again!
Come on.
Hey!
The Libyans.
No!
You bastard!
Go!
Doc!
No.
You're alive.
Bulletproof vest?
How did you know?
I, I never got a chance to tell you.
What about all that talk?
About screwing up future events?
The space-time continuum?
Well, I figured...
what the hell?
So, how far ahead are you going?
About 30 years.
It's a nice round number.
Look me up when
you get there, alright?
I guess, I'll be about 47?
I will.
Take care.
You too.
Right.
Bye-bye, Einie.
Oh, and watch that re-entry.
It's a little bumpy.
You bet.
♪ So take me away ♪
♪  I don't mind ♪
♪ But you better promise me ♪
♪ I'll be back in time ♪
♪ Gotta get back in time ♪
♪ Get me back in time ♪
What a nightmare!
If Paul calls me,
tell him I'm working
at the boutique late tonight.
Linda, first of all,
I'm not your answering service.
Second of all, somebody
named Greg or Craig...
called you just a little while ago.
Well, which one was it,
Greg or Craig?
I don't know. I can't keep up
with all of your boyfriends.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
What the hell is this?
Breakfast.
What? You sleep in your clothes
again last night?
Yeah. I...
Yeah. What are,
what are you wearing, Dave?
Marty?
I always wear a suit to the office.
You alright?
Yeah.
I think we need a rematch.
- George.
- A, a rematch?
- Why? Were you cheating?
- No.
- Hello.
- Good morning.
Mom! Dad!
- What? Did you hit your head?
- Marty, are you alright?
You guys, you guys look great.
Mom, you, you look so thin.
Thank you, Marty.
George!
Good morning, sleepyhead.
Good morning, Dave.
Good morning, Mom.
- Linda.
- Good morning, Mom.
Oh Marty, I almost forgot.
Jennifer Parker called.
Oh, I sure like her, Marty.
She is such a sweet girl.
Isn't tonight the night
of the big date?
What? What, Ma?
Aren't you going up
to the lake tonight?
You've been planning it
for two weeks.
Um, Mom, we talked about this.
We're not gonna go to the lake.
- The car's wrecked.
- Wrecked?
- What happened?
When did this happen?
- And why wasn't I told?
- Quiet down.
I'm sure the car is fine.
Why am I always the last one
to know about these things?
See? There's Biff out there
waxing it right now.
Uh, now Biff,
I want to make sure that we get
two coats of wax this time, not just one.
I'm just finishing up
the second coat now.
Now Biff, don't con me.
Uh, I'm, I'm sorry, Mr. McFly.
I, I meant I was just starting
on the second coat.
Yeah, Biff.
What a character!
Always trying to get away
with something.
Have to stay on top of Biff
ever since high school.
Although, if it wasn't for him...
We never would have fallen in love.
That's right.
Mr. McFly!
Mr. McFly, this just arrived.
Oh, hi, Marty.
I think it's your new book.
Oh, honey.
- Oh.
- Your first novel.
Like I've always told you:
Put your mind to it,
you can accomplish anything.
Oh, Marty.
Marty here's your keys.
You're all waxed up,
ready for tonight.
Keys?
How about a ride, mister?
Jennifer.
Oh, you're a sight for sore eyes!
Let me look at you.
Marty, you're acting like
you haven't seen me in a week.
I haven't.
You okay?
Is everything alright?
Oh, yeah.
Everything is great.
Marty!
You've got to come back with me!
Where?
Back to the future.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing, Doc?
I need fuel.
Go ahead. Quick.
Get in the car.
No, no, no, Doc.
I just got here, okay?
Jennifer's here. We're gonna
take the new truck for a spin.
Well, bring her along.
This concerns her, too.
Wait a minute, Doc.
What are you talking about?
What happens to us in the future?
We become assholes or something?
No, no, no, no, Marty.
Both you and Jennifer turn out fine.
It's your kids, Marty.
Something has got
to be done about your kids.
Hey, Doc, we better back up.
We don't have enough road to get up to 88.
Roads?
Where we're going,
we don't need roads.
♪ Tell me, doctor ♪
♪ Where are we going this time ♪
♪ Is this the 50's ♪
♪ Or 1999 ♪
♪ All I wanted to do ♪
♪ Was play my guitar and sing ♪
♪ So take me away ♪
♪ I don't mind ♪
♪ But you better promise me ♪
♪ I'll be back in time ♪
♪ Gotta get back in time ♪
♪ Don't bet your future ♪
♪ On one roll of the dice ♪
♪ Better remember ♪
♪ Lightning never strikes twice ♪
♪ Please don't drive at 88 ♪
♪ Don't want to be late again ♪
♪ So take me away ♪
♪ I don't mind ♪
♪ But you better promise me ♪
♪ I'll be back in time ♪
♪ Gotta get back in time ♪