How are we doin'?
Starting route
to National Institutes of Health.
Sorry Cliff, I'm trying... I'm trying
to get the right security
to get into the right entrance.
- This is a whole new life here.
- Yeah, I know, I...
It is just before 7:00
in the morning
and Dr. Fauci is beginning
one of his 12-hour days.
It is a schedule he keeps six days a week.
Ten seconds. There you go.
It's always ten seconds.
Tony Fauci
has not been elected to anything.
He's had the same job for nearly 40 years.
That means the majority of American voters
never even indirectly picked him.
Yet, in the last four months,
Fauci has become one
of the most powerful people in the world.
For more on
what we know about the coronavirus,
we're joined now by Dr. Anthony Fauci.
He's Director of the National Institute
of Allergy and Infectious Diseases.
Dr. Fauci, how concerned should we be?
For a while,
life is not gonna be the way it used to be
in the United States.
We have to just accept that
if we wanna do what's best
for the American public.
How does this compare
to anything that you've ever dealt with?
You always almost have
a fog of war about it.
It's not that different
than the very early years
of the HIV epidemic.
Fauci is the Director
of the National Institute of Allergies
and Infectious Diseases
and is the Commanding Officer
in the nation's scientific war
against AIDS.
He is also a target of critics who charge
the government's response to AIDS
- has been one of confusion.
The only people
in charge of AIDS are incompetent hacks.
I mean, what the hell
are these people doing?
They're not producing drugs.
Fire Fauci! Fire Fauci!
Do wear a mask,
don't wear a mask.
Don't worry about the coronavirus.
Never reopen schools
until we have a cure for coronavirus.
Dr. Fauci has been
at this for 50 years. He is an icon.
He is the most published researcher
in the world.
I think Donald Trump
is the sixth president he has served.
He was very involved
in the early AIDS epidemic, Ebola...
You name it, he's been there.
Did he get ventilators prepared?
Did he get masks prepared?
Did he get gloves prepared?
No. No, he did nothing.
He should be fired,
indicted and thrown in jail
and it's time we have a revolution
in this country.
I'd actually like to go back
to the old times of Tudor England.
I'd put the heads on pikes
as a warning to federal bureaucrats,
either get with the program
or you're gone.
God help us. God help us!
Hmm.
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah, you're good.
So, they're turning down
TB requests for vaccine research?
- Correct.
- Unbelievable.
I asked specifically
"Who said 'no'?"
and it was the White House.
So, I guess we're back at our stalemate.
And, you know, I didn't know
when I pushed back on it,
the answer I got was that they want
the focus to be on the economy.
I don't get how talking about vaccine
isn't important about the economy.
If you get a vaccine,
the economy will open.
So, what's the problem?
- Yeah.
- I don't... I don't get it.
People are tired
of hearing Fauci and all these idiots,
all these people,
these people that have gotten it wrong.
Fauci's a disaster.
I mean, this guy, if I listen to him...
Right now,
a lot of people think I'm the bad guy.
Every time he goes
on television there's always a bomb.
If we listen to him, we have 700,
800,000 deaths right now.
So if there's a recorder on,
you can have it just the way it's done.
I mean, I'm the bad guy
to an entire subset of people...
because I represent something
that is uncomfortable for them.
It's called the truth.
I tell the President exactly...
- I don't doubt that.
- what the scientific data is
and what the evidence is.
Secretary of State Pompeo
is extremely busy.
I'd like him to go back
to the State Department
or, as they call it,
the Deep State Department. You know, Mike.
I'd like to have him go back
and do his job.
So, does anybody have any questions?
I know I shouldn't be touching
my face, but...
I'm so good at my job.
How can he be so bad at his?
So the protests don't increase
the spread of the virus?
I didn't say that.
You're putting words in my mouth.
Is somebody born a craven partisan hack
or do you become one?
I grew up in Bensonhurst,
which was a somewhat tough neighborhood
in Brooklyn. You know,
everyone was striving.
Nothing was taken for granted.
There wasn't a lot of head hanging
in those days, you know?
Part of the culture back then
when you were a kid
is that you didn't get intimidated
by a lot of things.
Or, as we used to say,
"You didn't take any shit from anybody."
I don't want to hurt him.
He's been there for about 350 years.
Anthony Fauci, this fraud?
This swamp creature?
And who is now forced
to go on his power walks
with a security detail,
because he's received death threats.
My job is to do whatever I can
to get us out of this outbreak.
My weapon, in addition to the science,
is speaking to the American public.
What keeps me grounded
is the enormity of the problem.
And just a very deep sense
of responsibility...
that calls for all of the things
that I've been trained for,
dating back to when I was going to school.
In high school, I had
this early cultivation of public service.
Regis High School was driven by these guys
in black cassocks called Jesuit Priests.
The Jesuit philosophy is men for others.
You think about what you can do
for society
and what you can do for other people.
It's what drove me to go
to medical school.
There wasn't a minute that I really
didn't treasure at Cornell Medical School.
I loved clinical medicine.
Every single cell in my body was,
like, focused in this.
It was the first time in my life
that somebody's life is my responsibility.
At the end of my junior year,
it was the Vietnam War.
And every physician
is automatically drafted.
But you had some choices.
You could do public health service,
Navy, Army or Air Force.
So, I put in public health service first.
Second I put Navy, then Army,
and then Air Force.
And, sure enough, I get a call
from the National Institutes of Health.
The NIH was and is really
the mecca of biomedical research.
Here in the laboratories
at NIH, much of the research is basic.
Clinical medicine is practiced at NIH
because it contributes to research
rather than because of the patient's need
for medical attention.
Virtually everyone
who was anyone in academic medicine
in this country...
had spent some time here.
And it was like entering
into a magical world.
When I first came down,
what I really wanted to do
was do three years,
bingo, and go back to New York
and become the Chief Resident
at the New York Hospital.
Back then, that was your ticket
to a private practice on Park Avenue.
You know, I was a kid from Brooklyn
and Brooklyn to Manhattan
is like New York State to Rome.
But as I got to learn more about myself,
the idea of discovery,
the idea of having an impact
on a lot more people...
trying to figure out diseases
that people were dying from,
that's what really captured me.
So, I became the Senior Investigator
at the NIH.
I met Tony very shortly after I came
to the NIH.
Tony was a Lab Chief at that point
in time.
He was a long-term single guy.
Totally dedicated to work.
He worked more hours
than almost anybody I've ever known.
My wife and I would sometimes tease Tony.
Because he had several female companions
through the years.
I'd go on a date every once
in a while,
but I was completely buried in my work.
I actually remember very vividly,
and hearing this
from other people as well,
if you're working
with one of Tony Fauci's patients,
you'd better take good care
of that patient
because he will demand it of you.
All of this discussion of vasculitis
is merely academic.
At the time,
I was focused on vasculitis
which is an inflammation of blood vessels
that leads to kidney failure,
lung failure and things like that.
There was a patient who was a senator
from Brazil.
He didn't speak any English and I said,
"Well, I can't have a conversation
with this guy,
so who speaks Portuguese around here?"
So they called this nurse,
this Christine Grady,
into the room, um...
and she stand by the bedside
and I looked at her, I says, "Wow!"
"Who's this?"
I had just spent two years
in Brazil
and so my Portuguese
was then pretty good.
And we had this meeting
in the patient's room
and I said, "He would like to go home."
I said, "Okay. That's fine to do that,
"but he's gotta understand,
these ulcers are not completely healed.
"He's gotta keep his legs elevated
and he's gotta change
the dressings frequently."
So, he speaks Portuguese back.
I'm, sort of, sitting there
waiting to hear.
The patient said to me...
"There's no way I'm going to do that.
I'm going to go to the beach every day."
He lived on the beach, near the beach.
"And I'm going to go dancing at night.
I've been in the hospital for months
and you expect me to go home
and sit with my leg in the air?"
And I, sort of, gulped and thought,
what the heck am I going to do now?
She turned to me and looked at me
and said, "He said he's gonna do exactly
like you said."
I said, "Good. You can go."
A day later,
I saw Dr. Fauci in the hallway,
who said to me,
"I'd like to see you in my office."
And I was certain that I was caught
and going to be either reprimanded
or fired.
So, she comes into the office
with a great deal of trepidation.
She sits down and I look at her and I say,
"Would you like to go to dinner?"
So, that was the beginning.
When we got to know each other
really well, she says,
"You know, remember that conversation
that we had in the room?
Well, I actually told you a white lie."
I think Tony came
to the NIH young and ambitious
and looking for a challenge, I think,
and found it.
I was sitting in my office
and I saw this... article...
in a publication called MMWR.
Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report.
And it reported five men...
curiously all gay men, who developed
a very strange pneumonia
called pneumocystis pneumonia.
And, being a busy young investigator
at the time,
I took it, I put it in my desk
and I said, "This must be a fluke.
It's gonna go away."
One month later, another MMWR appears.
This time, 26 gay men...
who not only had pneumocystis pneumonia,
but had Kaposi's sarcoma,
a tumor, a cancer,
seen in people whose immune system
is remarkably suppressed.
And I remember looking at that
and going, "Oh, my God.
"There's no way that this is a fluke.
This is a brand new disease."
I actually got goosebumps.
So, I made a decision
that I was going to completely change
the direction of my research.
He had lots of critics
on the NIH campus.
They thought he was making a mistake.
That he was taking on a disease
in an area of science
that was going nowhere
and that he was gonna ruin
his career basically.
So, I wrote an article
in 1981...
saying that if we think this disease
is gonna stay confined
to a very discreet group of people,
that it's not gonna explode,
we're kidding ourselves.
I submitted it to a major journal.
They rejected it
because one of the reviewers said
I was being too alarmist.
So right away, he had
to fight... Not fight but push back on,
you know, people who said,
"But wait a minute,
you can't put money into this
and take it away from other things."
And he said, "But we have to,
because we have to learn
about this disease."
I recruited young people
to work with me.
Henry Masur, who was
on the junior faculty at Cornell,
Cliff Lane had just finished
his fellowship
and the three of us
became the Three Musketeers of HIV
here at NIH.
Our focus at the time was
the adult human immune system.
There weren't a lot of groups
that had that as a focus.
You just knew you had to do something.
Because you thought
you could do something.
Scientists
at the National Center For Disease Control
in Atlanta today released the results
of a study
which shows that the lifestyle
of some male homosexuals
has triggered an epidemic
of a rare form of cancer.
Researchers know of 413 people
who have contracted the condition
in the past year.
One third have died
and none have been cured.
How many friends have you lost
to this disease?
Twenty.
- Twenty?
- Yes.
And you have
still more friends who are sick?
Very ill.
Jane, can you imagine what it must be like
if you had lost 20 of your friends
- in the last 18 months?
- No.
- And you don't know why?
- No cause, no cure.
Investigators
have examined the habits
of homosexuals for clues.
That I was in the fast lane at one time
in terms of the way that I lived my life
and now I'm not.
A-I-D-S. AIDS.
The most frightening initials
in America today.
A medical mystery that destroys
the immune system
and leaves our bodies defenseless
against unusual and deadly infections.
I was going out
and meeting people,
trying to find a lover.
I didn't know that, you know,
that there were things out there
so secretly hidden
that it was gonna destroy my life.
I had been trained
as an infectious disease doc...
and as an immunologist.
If ever there was a disease
that I was made for...
it's this disease.
Dr. Fauci, can you tell us
what do we know?
What are the best clues you've got?
We do have some clues
that it may be a viral agent
that is likely infecting immune cells
that are necessary to fight
certain types of infections...
We didn't know what it was.
We strongly suspected it was a virus.
There is, right now at the present time,
no known cure for AIDS.
We don't even know what the agent is,
much less how to cure it.
Like ink spreading on a blotter,
AIDS has now been identified
in over 35 states
and 16 foreign countries.
It was an evolving picture...
rapidly and frighteningly.
For the first time North America,
the world's leading experts
on sexually transmitted diseases
meet to share the latest research data.
From the National Institutes of Health,
Dr. Anthony Fauci,
who directs the research on how AIDS
affects the body's immune system.
From what we know now,
once you get the underlying immune defect,
you do not recover from it,
which is a very, very important thing.
A small army of dedicated medical warriors
is trying to combat this killer.
In the laboratories,
researchers are scrambling for a cure.
In the hospitals and doctors' offices,
the front line soldiers
face a losing battle
and must content themselves
with the little victories for now.
You know, every once in a while
when you're involved
in a difficult situation you get bad news,
bad news and then sometimes
encouraging news comes along
to make you feel a little better.
It was all bad, bad, worse,
bad, worse, bad, worse.
It was just so unbelievably... frustrating
when you're used to...
being able to fix things
and you're just not really fixing
anything.
It is very difficult to work
with young people who you care for,
become quite attached to
and in some cases even identify with
and to watch them overtime
get sicker and die.
It is not just one patient,
but one after another after another.
And I had had jobs prior to this one
where people were very sick
and many of my patients had died,
but this was different...
because everybody was, sort of,
at the prime of their life.
Back then, when you got sick
you were gone fast.
Seven, eight, nine months
and it was horrible deaths.
It was a time when all of us
were very scared
and there was very little
that we could do.
I found out in late '85, November 1985...
I was 24.
I didn't know anything
about the politics of AIDS.
I just knew that it was all of a sudden
this terrible scare story
and the country was in a panic about it
and that it was 100 percent fatal.
I was living in the Bronx
with my lover Jeff, who was diagnosed
with Kaposi's sarcoma.
For me, the AIDS epidemic started then.
I went to my doctor
and the minute he put the needle in my arm
I knew I was positive, I knew it.
And then I avoided his calls.
For three and a half weeks,
I was able to avoid his calls...
and then he found me and he said
that I was HIV positive.
I said, "Well, what's the prognosis or..."
He said, "18 months."
Breathe in and out with your mouth open.
You know, one of my patients
who had cytomegalovirus retinitis.
Cytomegalovirus is a virus
that chews up the retina.
And he was gradually losing vision.
He would walk in, he'd say,
"Dr. Fauci, how are you?"
He was always upbeat. He'd walk in.
I would smile. You know,
he'd make comments,
"I love your smile.
You have a great smile."
And I'd go in every day and morning,
afternoon, evening
and then, one day,
we walked in in the morning
and I walked in and went up to the desk
and he said, "Who's there?"
And it was clear, you know,
that he gone completely blind.
And it was like...
And we were standing around the bed
saying, "Now what?" you know?
And it was... it was terrible,
because he lost his vision completely.
Yeah.
It's affecting you now.
- Yeah.
- Why?
Uh,
post-traumatic stress syndrome.
That's what it is.
My early understanding
of what my dad was doing was...
there's something happening
that's affecting people,
that's hurting people,
that's killing people.
When I think about my dad growing up,
I certainly think about that seriousness,
that intensity and working hard
and wanting to do the right thing.
That's his compass.
At the same time, I also think
about a person that I think
very few people get to see.
Which is someone who is funny
and weird and really playful.
This is a record
for the month of July, 1988.
We've been over 100,
so how many days in a row?
- Several.
- Too many.
Well, we're just sitting here
hanging out by the pool on a Sunday...
Sunday morning.
Jenny and Daddy are gonna go swimming!
Are you gonna go swimming?
Are you gonna show everybody
how you could stay up straight
in the water?
- Show Mommy.
- Come on.
Yeah. You've got water in your eye?
When Chris and I were knee deep
in responding to this historic pandemic.
We wanted to and did raise a family.
- Now you've got us all?
- Yeah.
Okay, Nan.
- Here we are.
Here's Jenny and her baby sister.
Jennifer, Mommy, and Daddy.
Jennifer and her baby sister Megan.
Hi, Megan.
- Oh, don't you look pretty!
- Look, it's coming off.
It's March 30th, 1989...
and Megan is getting herself a bath.
Jenny first and Megan,
then Alison.
- Hi, Momma.
- Are you the audience with me?
Yes.
Merry Christmas.
Whoa, don't fall!
January seventh, the blizzard of 1996.
Probably the largest snow storm
in the history of Washington, D.C...
A foot. It's a foot
and it's gonna be two feet.
When our children were little,
he used to work all the time.
And there were times
when they wouldn't see him
for a couple of days sometimes.
I wouldn't say I neglected
the raising of the children,
but I did not sacrifice
professional things...
as much as maybe I should have.
I was not going
to every soccer match,
every track meet, every swim meet.
- Yes.
- Whoo! Yeah.
Chris did everything.
But we did something that I think
physically is a little unhealthy,
I don't recommend it for people,
but it worked.
We decided that
we were gonna have dinner...
together every night
no matter how late the dinner was.
He would come home
from like a 12 or 13-hour day of work
and he would come in the kitchen
and start dancing with my mom.
I'm like, "Dad, we want to eat dinner.
Please come and sit down."
But we understood that when he's working,
which is all of the time,
he's laser focused.
Rather than name
each and every one of these,
why don't I just talk
about asthma analogy,
I'll mention transportation, autoimmunity,
vaccine developments, skip cancer,
go to immune mediated disease
and then end up with AIDS.
AIDS brings a new level
of pressure and public attention to NIH,
and especially to Dr. Fauci,
who already manages
three full time jobs at NIH.
Administrator, physician,
research scientist.
Pardon my eating,
I'm having my lunch before the hearing,
so if I'm eating in your ear,
don't worry.
We don't have the answer.
We're trying to get the answer,
but we're letting the science take us
where it's taking us.
Researchers believe that they have made
a monumental breakthrough
in the fight against AIDS.
The deadly disease that attacks
the body's immune system.
US Government scientists announced
in Washington today,
they have isolated a virus
they believe causes AIDS.
The breakthrough came
at the National Institutes of Health,
where a way was found
to mass produce the AIDS virus,
study it and most importantly,
to test blood for it.
- Fauci?
- F-A-U-C-I.
We found that we had a virus.
It was really quite transforming.
Now I have it in my hand,
I know what the hell it is.
You know, I have it in a test tube.
It's not like this thing
that's floating around
that we have no idea what it is.
There is an inherent fear...
built into viruses.
The lives of millions of Americans
are being severely disrupted
by the coronavirus pandemic.
Schools, work, even iconic institutions
like Broadway and Disneyworld
are shut down. Experts say...
When we hear about one
that is taking off...
it really rings all of the alarm bells.
Seeing a vibrant city
like New York
resembling a bit of a ghost town
was a moving... feeling for me.
Very emotional...
because, you know, I grew up as a kid
roaming around Manhattan.
And to see it empty
was just very, very shocking
in many respects.
But community spread was rampant
and we had to make a decision
to shut everything down.
The tri-state region now topping
90,000 confirmed cases of COVID-19
and more than 1,500 deaths.
Hospitals are reeling
with New York City's mayor,
warning they will run out of supplies
by this weekend.
Okay. VRC.
Sure.
As soon as we heard
that in Wuhan these cases
apparently appeared,
we had no idea
if it was gonna turn out to be bad.
We just knew it is conceivable
that this could turn out to be a pandemic.
My group here
in the Vaccine Research Center said...
"As soon as we get a sequence,
let's go for it."
The sequence came out,
I believe, on the ninth.
We had the meeting on the tenth.
By the time we got to the 15th,
we were already in the process
of making it
and then 63, 65 days later,
we were in a phase one trial.
Scientists all across the world
are now racing to find a vaccine
that can help combat
the coronavirus in the future.
The National Institutes of Health
and a Massachusetts company Moderna
are behind the record speed
clinical trials.
We've been hearing a lot
about the Moderna vaccine,
that's an mRNA vaccine.
This is different from other vaccines.
It uses mRNA to basically teach the body
how to fight the virus.
But never before have we seen
a successful mRNA vaccine.
When we were confronted with this virus,
there are a lot of very smart people
at the NIH who put their heads together
and realized that mRNA vaccines
could be a real option.
If it works,
it's a potentially safer and faster path.
Shortening the development process
from decades to years.
Even though we didn't all know about it,
there was a lot of research being done
for many, many years with the NIH
towards making mRNA vaccines.
- I think it's gonna work.
- I do too.
I mean, I really do.
We had been priming
the pump for years before
with the platform technology,
in this case mRNA.
So, as soon as we found out that we were
dealing with a brand new virus,
we said, "This what we do.
We make vaccines. Let's do it."
This is a very exciting technology
at the mRNA vaccines
and it's extremely exciting,
but I don't believe a single one of them
has ever reached market.
It's incredibly impressive
that they made that call,
because it's a bold one.
It took some amount of courage
to move forward with something
that you know isn't an absolute certainty.
I talked to Tony Fauci yesterday,
the Head of the National Institute
of Allergy and Infectious Diseases.
A vaccine is in the works,
but it's a couple of years away.
The fastest we had ever developed
a vaccine before that was for mumps
and that took four years.
And so, we're able to move
very, very fast,
so as soon as we get the phase one dose
out of the NIH,
we'll be able to start phase two
right away.
You're talking over the next few months
you think you could have a vaccine?
- Correct.
- With phase two.
Yeah. You won't have a vaccine.
You'll have a vaccine to go into testing.
Testing, yes.
Well, you have the greatest companies
in the world sitting around the table.
I mean, Johnson & Johnson and Pfizer
and all of the companies. Gilead.
Uh, you have all of these great companies
and that's what they're saying,
so I think that...
Would you make sure you get
the President the information
that a vaccine that you make
and start testing in a year
is not a vaccine that's deployable.
So, he's asking the question
"When is it gonna be deployable?"
and that is gonna be, at the earliest,
a year to a year and half,
no matter how fast you go.
I met with the President and with Tony
and a few others in the room
on a couple of occasions.
Oftentimes it was Tony
who was seen as the main proponent
of the unpopular view.
You take a solid flu vaccine,
you don't think that would have an impact
or much of an impact on corona?
No, no. Probably not.
Can you talk
about your early meetings
with the President
and your impressions of him?
Is that something
that you're willing to share?
Yikes!
How deep do you want to get?
We had task force meetings
very regularly.
First, a few times a week and then,
almost literally every single day.
We're live now
at the White House in the briefing room,
where moments from now President Trump
will hold a news conference
talking about
his administration's response
to the coronavirus outbreak.
We had press conferences
that were a hybrid of a press conference.
It wasn't totally dominated
by the scientists.
Thank you very much.
The President would get up
with his style
and... for reasons that none of us
could understand,
it was always confronting the press.
What do you say to Americans
who are watching right now who are scared?
I say that you're a terrible reporter.
That's what I say. Go ahead.
Because of that,
the public health messages
got a bit muddled.
The President might get up,
and out of nowhere, say something
that we would all go,
"What's that all about?"
President Trump's
been touting an anti-malaria drug
that he says
could help treat the coronavirus.
So, how beneficial is hydroxychloroquine?
My next guest says doctors
are already using this treatment
in the United States successfully.
For me, I'm absolutely convinced
this is what saved my life.
It was the typical example
that we scientists shudder at.
Joe Jones tells you that I did this
and I got better, therefore, it works.
And it was very clear
that there was no evidence whatsoever
that hydroxychloroquine... worked.
And that's when things got complicated.
Yes, John.
A question
for Dr. Fauci, if I could.
Dr. Fauci, it was explained yesterday
there has been some promise
with hydroxychloroquine,
this potential therapy for people
who are infected with coronavirus.
Is there any evidence to suggest
that, as with malaria,
it might be used as a prophylaxis
against COVID-19?
No. The answer is no and the evidence
that you're talking about, John,
is anecdotal evidence.
That was the first time that publicly,
with all the cameras rolling,
I just had to get up and contradict him.
But the information
that you are referring to specifically
is anecdotal. It was not done
in a controlled clinical trial,
so you really can't make
any definitive statement about it.
When I stepped back
from the podium,
I remembered the advice that I got
decades earlier by my good friend
who said, "Whenever you go
into the White House, you should assume
"that there's a possibility
that you're not gonna get asked back,
because you might have to tell somebody
something they didn't want to hear."
And as I stepped back I said,
"Well, this may be it."
I think...
without saying too much,
I'm probably more of a fan of that
than... maybe than anybody.
He was so much in his own world
that... I don't...
He didn't react in a way of saying
how dare you contradict me
I'm the President?
It was like, I'll say what I'm gonna say,
you say what you're gonna say.
Let's see if it works.
It might and it might not.
I happen to feel good about it,
but who knows?
I've been right a lot.
Let's see what happens.
- John.
- Can I come back to the science
- and the logistics?
- You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
The units that were ordered,
are they for...
It just was
a remarkable sort of back and forth
between someone who's using
their gut instincts,
not scientifically based,
not evidence based
against, you know,
a venerable scientist who kept
sort of, on the fly, it seems,
trying to fact check the President.
I just had never seen anything like it.
I think Tony Fauci probably has one
of the hardest jobs in America right now.
Communication is not ancillary
to fighting an epidemic.
Communication is central
I'd like to provide some basic
but important facts about Ebola
and its transmission.
During the crises
that we faced in the Obama Administration,
it was particularly Dr. Fauci
who brought this extraordinary sobriety...
and rationality and fact based,
evidence based leadership to the table.
The Centers for Disease Control
is closely monitoring what's become
the largest Ebola outbreak in history.
Ebola has been
ravaging West Africa since March
and shocked disease specialists
when it hopped a border by plane.
The moment Ebola
began spreading in cities,
we were at the edge of an abyss.
From the front lines
of West Africa
to the front door of America,
an all-out push to get ahead of Ebola.
I think we've got to let
the science guide us.
The outbreak
that the President said
was unlikely to come here is now here.
Our nation
was really wired into a frenzy of anxiety
about whether this
is gonna sweep across the country
and take us all with it.
Right now we have a devastating epidemic
in West Africa
and we're having an epidemic of fear
in the United States,
so we've got to continue to try
and educate people
about what they need to
or do not need to be afraid of.
Dr. Fauci clearly understood
and clearly conveyed
that there was a wise,
scientifically driven way
to deal with this and a hysterical way
to deal with it.
The reason we are having
this very difficult situation
in the African countries
is because they don't have the system
to be able to contain it.
If they had the system,
we would not be seeing
all of this suffering and dying
in West Africa.
If that's the case and if it's one case
in the United States now,
as we know it is...
why are we having
news conferences like this
and why are we all so afraid?
Ebola is a terrifying virus.
It causes you to bleed
through your orifices.
It's transmissible through bodily fluids.
It's not, therefore as easy to catch
as a COVID-19 or a flu virus
because it's not airborne.
But it is much more deadly.
The American part of dealing
with Ebola here in this country
took basically a 90 degree turn
this weekend.
A nurse in Dallas
becomes the first person
to contract Ebola in the United States.
Just moments ago, Nurse Nina Pham
left the city for an NIH facility.
I believe that it's Nina Pham.
It looks like
she's walking off the plane there, Don.
- Yeah, very slowly.
- When we were called upon...
to care for one of the nurses
who got infected, Tony led that charge.
She came here at 11:54.
All of us have been up all night.
We haven't learned a lot
about the virus yet.
We're taking care of the patient.
Even some of our staff
and our community
were a little reluctant
to go near the doctors and the nurses
who were taking care of Ebola patients
because they thought
we were going to infect people
in the community,
which was impossible.
That was not gonna happen.
So, when Nina completely recovered,
we decided
we would publicly discharge her.
As we were waiting in the lobby,
I was saying,
"Maybe I should do something here
that could change around the stigma."
Our patient Nina Pham is free of Ebola.
Nina?
I wanted people to see
that I was not afraid of hugging someone
who was completely recovered.
I mean, it was, like, click, click,
click, click all over the place.
- We love you, Nina.
- Yeah.
To be able to turn
that around and say,
"Here's somebody who had it
and she's fine,"
it's a counter to that visceral fear
of contagion.
Tony has an ability
to deal with fear
and a really serious understanding
of how to speak about... uncertainty
and threat...
to a terrified general population.
The AIDS problem in America
is only getting worse
with every passing day
and there is no sign
that it will get better any time soon.
The National Academy of Sciences
is warning of an AIDS catastrophe
unless the government is willing to spend
big money for education and research.
Had this disease afflicted children
or members of the chamber of commerce,
I'm sure the Reagan Administration
would have been breaking down
all doors in order to deal with it.
As the numbers increase,
so does something else. Fear.
The AIDS hotline.
Most of the callers besieging
the country's AIDS hotlines
are heterosexuals,
panicked at the realization
that they too could be at risk.
I personally will tell my child
if someone has AIDS, stay away from them.
At the time,
people were very concerned
about transmission.
We knew how this was transmitted,
but there was still this crazy stigma.
Even though I was a researcher
and a physician scientist,
I really wanted to get out
and address that.
One of the nation's
outstanding researchers on AIDS
is Dr. Anthony Fauci.
Dr. Fauci, thank you very much
for coming in today.
Anthony Fauci, MD,
National Institute of Health,
make us feel better
about these anxieties.
It appears that the transmissibility
of AIDS is through repeated sexual contact
and/or in IV drug users
in sharing needles.
There is absolutely no evidence at all
that AIDS can be transmitted
by casual contact, by touching,
by any kind of normal social interactions
that you might have with anyone.
So, I think that the fears
may be understandable,
but they're not scientifically sound.
One of the issues
I had to push back against
is that this was kind
of somebody else's disease.
Do you think
that maybe the guilt
that the gay community
has been dealing with
could be a reason
for the breakdown of the immune system?
No.
What is your response to those who say
only a small, unsavory group of people
is affected by it?
Therefore, it is not something that those
who lead the straight and narrow life
should be as concerned about there.
To say because someone has
a particular lifestyle
that they're unsavory,
I think is objectionable.
These individuals who are infected,
be they homosexuals
or IV drug abusers, are people.
People who deserve compassion,
who deserve care and who deserve concern.
We need to distinguish
between unfair discrimination
- and fair discrimination.
- Oh!
And they are reservoir
of a host of contagious diseases.
I'm gonna have to remove the mic
and we'll move on down this way.
In the light
of that extraordinary outburst,
I think, from a scientific standpoint,
it should be really established
so that everybody understands
that there's nothing intrinsic
about homosexuality
that has to do with AIDS,
and her response was a very good example
of the kind of discrimination
that we're talking about.
There's only one source
of the AIDS plague,
the homosexual community
is committing genocide
and we are not speaking
and telling the truth to them.
There's religious groups claiming
this is God's revenge
and HIV gave them the excuse
to increase their level of hatred
and their level of discrimination.
Some people have been evicted
from their homes,
either by their roommates
or by their landlords,
because of people's fear
of contamination
through their kind of casual
social contact.
If one is against
the reservoir of the disease,
then he's got to be against the reservoir
of the disease,
whether it's cows or monkeys
or homosexuals.
The risk for AIDS
is not being a homosexual man
and the risk for AIDS
is not any of the other groups.
The risk is the behavior.
That's a very important thing.
It was an important experience,
because it got me
to see beyond the individual patient...
beyond the research
and development of the drugs...
what this disease was doing in society.
With some 40,000 reported cases
and 20,000 dead or dying,
AIDS remains the gay plague.
There's some similarities
with this pandemic
in the sense that people naturally want
to look for someone to blame.
We had the greatest year
and then, we got hit
with the China plague, right?
We got hit with the China plague.
China has put 40,000,000 Americans out
of work and killed 100,000 Americans.
It's really convenient for politicians
to have a scapegoat like that,
because if they can blame another country,
if they can blame another group of people,
then they can absolve themselves
of responsibility.
Tensions over when
and how fast to reopen
dominate American life. States and cities
weigh two overriding factors.
Economic devastation
and nearly 84,000 deaths
in the United States.
When you pull back
and the virus is doing this,
it's only gonna do that.
It's not gonna turn around and come down.
Some people may think
it's gonna be like a light switch,
on and off. You know,
we're either out and we're in.
It's just not gonna be that way.
I don't think you're the end-all,
I don't think you're the one person
that gets to make a decision.
We can listen to your advice,
but there are people on the other side
saying there's not going to be a surge
and that we can safely open the economy
and the facts will bear this out.
I have never made myself out
to be the end all and only voice of this.
I'm a scientist, a physician
and a public health official.
I give advice according
to the best scientific evidence.
This phenomena of just telling the truth,
you know,
has made him both, an enemy
and a rock star, you know, all at once.
I want people to know
who they're getting in Tony Fauci.
The head and the heart that comes together
in your body is the real deal.
You're on socks, you're on mugs.
There's Fauci Friday.
Yeah, the National Institutes of hotness!
Just try to stay six feet away.
The man is out there fighting
to keep people healthy
and everyone is just, like,
"Drop you pants. Show us that PhD."
It's been totally surreal
to walk past a bookstore
in my neighborhood and see,
like, a candle with my dad's face on it.
It's like, I don't know
that that will ever feel...
um, not totally disorienting
and strange.
Excuse me, don't go outside
without your mask.
Called it Fauci Spring
and people kinda freaked out
about this one.
I've just found him very honest,
trustworthy. Kind of like a super hero.
It's amusing, it's interesting,
but you can't take it seriously,
because then you'll start thinking
that you're something that you're not.
However, built into that...
are some fun things.
We welcome Dr. Anthony Fauci.
Fauci's throw was just a bit outside.
Unfortunately, it turns out the man,
like all of us,
has a flaw.
There's a campaign to make you
the People Magazine
Sexiest Man of the Year.
- Why is this happening?
I have become "a symbol
for something that isn't really me."
It's something that has been created.
Which, I'm fine with that,
as long as it helps people.
But they need to realize
that when the world gets back to normal,
for sure, I am not the sexiest man
in the world.
In the US, before this pandemic,
if you pushed someone to name a scientist,
I bet they couldn't have.
And now they can say Tony Fauci.
But, along with all of this attention
and fame came the criticism.
Anthony Fauci is doing blogs,
he's doing Steph Curry's podcasts.
Can't he get on a lab coat
and make some progress?
He's running for something.
Does anybody know what?
Because, above all,
you must never mock
the sainted Anthony Fauci.
Tony's been criticized for a lot of things
during this pandemic.
Some of those he deserves,
like the mask guidance.
I think that was confusing for people.
In March, Fauci told 60 Minutes
there's no reason
to be walking around with a mask.
Well, there was.
He felt he was going by the best
of what science offered at the time
and he's obviously been beaten up about it
quite a bit.
But it still is something I wonder about.
Early on,
the White House Coronavirus Task Force
was told we really have
a shortage of masks.
And we didn't know at the time
that there was
a lot of asymptomatic spread.
We didn't know that.
Under those circumstances I said,
"We shouldn't really be wearing masks."
And then when we found out
that 50 percent of the transmissions
occur from someone without symptoms,
then it became clear,
holy smokes,
we really should be wearing a mask.
There's been questions
over the past couple of weeks,
where is Dr. Fauci?
Dr. Fauci's role minimized.
Yeah, apparently he hasn't spoken directly
with the President since June second.
We're seeing uptakes again
and nobody's hearing from you.
Yeah.
Do you still feel you have
some positive influence
through the Task Force
or is it just a waste of time now...
- Well...
- From the exterior,
it seems like a waste of time and Trump
is on a very different direction.
Well, I think you just nailed it there,
because right now everything
is about opening the economy
and opening all the states.
To my mind,
that's why the turning off
of your voice is such a tragedy.
You know, tell me to shut up...
because I keep blogging it...
but if you had a Twitter account,
you'd get literally millions of followers
- within the first 24 hours.
- So, let me ask you a question.
What does having a Twitter account
actually mean?
You've got to type some stuff in
and just send it, is that what it is?
Do you got to respond to things?
I don't have any minutes.
No, you don't have
to respond to anything.
I don't have any minutes in the day.
You're gonna get a million responses...
and you ignore them all
and then you start delivering
your classic public health messages,
avoiding politics...
but you've got millions of people
listening to you
and it's something
the White House wouldn't vet,
as long as you didn't cross
into the political realm.
Right.
Here's the bad part.
When you do testing to that extent,
you're gonna find more people,
you're gonna find more cases.
So I said to my people,
"Slow the testing down, please."
So, Dr. Fauci,
do you agree with that?
It's the opposite.
We're gonna be doing more testing,
not less.
When you want to give
the American people confidence
that they can trust the knowledge
and the wisdom
coming out the US government.
It behooves us to put the scientists
and the doctors front and center.
We're going
in the wrong direction.
If you look at the curves
of the new cases,
clearly we are not in total control
right now.
Well, Dr. Doom himself,
spreading more COVID panic
and undermining Trump's agenda.
Honestly, I think Trump
needs to send him back to his office
and shut the door and say,
"Very nice.
"Thank you so much for your thoughts.
We're moving on."
As a country, we went up,
came down,
but instead of going all the way down
we plateaued
at around 20,000 cases per day.
Trade advisor Peter Navarro
wrote this Op-Ed saying,
"Anthony Fauci has been wrong
about everything
I have interacted with him on."
What I've been trying to do
is to get people to realize
how important it is to do
the fundamental public health measures,
because if we don't do that,
we are afraid
things could actually get worse.
Why on earth would your Administration
be involved in a campaign at this point
to discredit Dr. Fauci?
Because we're not.
If one man from my Administration
doesn't like him
because he made a few mistakes.
Look, Dr. Fauci said,
"Don't wear masks,"
Dr. Fauci told me not to ban China,
it would be a big mistake.
Fire Fauci!
Fire Fauci, fire Fauci, fire Fauci!
Of course he was disturbed
by any way
in which these attacks
muddied the message
or created a distraction
from the real set of issues,
but the more personal stuff
that was upsetting to me
and my sisters and my mom.
He, as best as he could
and I don't know how he did it,
just put that off the table.
When someone attacks
I don't immediately fight back.
That's not my style.
I don't get into the fray.
And over the years,
which became decades,
that became my mantra.
Using the Godfather
as the great book of philosophy,
it's nothing personal,
it's strictly business.
We'll never be silent again.
- We'll never be silent again.
- Fight back.
Nineteen thousand people a day.
If 19,000 grandmothers or boy scouts
or 11 boy scouts had died,
we'd go bananas in this country.
Murder! Murder! Murder!
The only people in charge
of AIDS are incompetent hacks.
You know, the rage is so intense,
what do you do to make a government fight
to do something
to save 40,000 people?
My first evidence
that there was anger out there...
at the government's response
to HIV-AIDS was an article
which had the headline,
"An Open Letter To Incompetent Idiot.
"I Call You A Murderer,
Dr. Anthony Fauci."
And went on saying
just what a complete disaster I was.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I was this, I was that.
And I said,
"Oh, my God, what did I do to this guy?"
Dr. Anthony Fauci is God in AIDS research.
He's just been inhumane, I guess,
is the only thing I can say.
It was written by a man
named Larry Kramer,
who was a firebrand
that was leading a group called ACT UP.
Act up! Stand tall!
It's time for action, City Hall!
If you go ACT UP to a scientist
they go...
You know, ACT UP, my God.
You know, run away from ACT UP.
The demonstrations
are the work of ACT UP.
A group which believes
that with 76,000 Americans
already dead as a result of AIDS,
it is imperative
to get the message across,
even if people are sometimes given
to outrage because of the message.
As the deaths mounted...
there was a realization that
if we didn't do something,
we were all going to die
and the country would just let us die.
I'll never forget
the first meeting.
It was in the West Village.
And I went in and there was this energy.
It was just like, it...
It was indescribable. And I felt hopeful
for the first time.
None of us had a background
in science.
I was a lawyer,
somebody else was a graphic designer,
somebody else studied Russian poetry.
Science was not where we came from,
but we began to learn.
And... we started having questions
about the studies.
I'd probably come over Fauci's name
during my own research,
but it hadn't really clicked yet,
but all of a sudden we were talking
about Tony Fauci at ACT UP meetings.
Tony Fauci was... the enemy.
For me, I had just lost my partner.
I was...
in grief and we needed drugs.
We needed them yesterday.
ACT UP's focus
was always drugs into bodies.
That's what the motto was.
Make sure that
we could find treatment
for HIV and AIDS for people
and make sure that it was accessible
to everyone.
AIDS patients breaking the law,
in a desperate battle
to save their own lives.
Many are now treating themselves
with medications not yet approved
by the government.
We were fighting with the FDA
over access to an experimental drug
to treat the pneumonia
that was the leading cause of death
amongst people with AIDS.
It was an approved drug already
for cancer patients
that had immune suppression
and it worked for them.
And Tony said "No,
we're not really interested in that.
"We're interested in this drug AZT
and that's where we're gonna put
our resources."
About a year later,
I think 16 or 18,000 people with AIDS
died of PCP pneumonia.
And we accused him
of causing those deaths.
This government isn't equipped
to put 10,000 people into a trial.
It is so disorganized.
There are so many committees.
But it could be equipped.
If Tony Fauci were courageous enough
to whisper...
I want to stay away from the politics.
In President Bush's ear
let's do something about this plague.
It was a little confusing because I,
who had been knocking myself out,
trying to do the right thing,
was the object of the anger.
But then something happened
within me and I said,
"You know, something's going on
that I'm missing here."
And that's when I started
to really reach out.
It was pretty much the first
and only time, I think,
in ACT UP's early history
where anybody in government came to us.
ACT UP REP 1:
We invited him to come
to an ACT UP meeting.
He knew that he was gonna face an audience
that was hostile and distrustful.
ACT UP MEMBER 1:
It was quite a scene.
I went up there to listen to them
and to try and explain to them
the rationale
for why we were doing what we were doing,
even though they did not agree.
ACT UP MEMBER 2:
The criticism, the hostility,
it didn't really seem to phase him.
My first impression
was that we're dealing with Brooklyn here.
He got a complete grilling
and continued the conversation.
We didn't agree on everything
in that first meeting,
but their instincts were right.
And that started a series of dialogs
that did not stop the demonstrations.
It's a lie, it's a sham,
it won't work!
It's a lie, it's a sham!
Although we were making progress
in coming to some rapprochement,
as it were,
they still thought that something
wasn't happening quickly enough.
He did not want to do anything
that was considered rocking the boat
about scientific norms
and the scientific establishment.
If you don't forge ahead,
you get accused of being too slow.
I'm just gonna have to do what's right
and do my job
and know that this is the right thing
for biomedical science,
the right thing
for the health of this country.
How you design a clinical trial
and how you evaluate those results,
the time it takes to go from the beginning
up to the time it actually gets approved
were what you would refer to
as sacrosanct processes.
Rigidity was perfection.
The reasons I can't get any of these drugs
is because the leadership in this country
has failed to come up
with a plan of action.
Bottom line.
The government's AIDS research effort,
which he is supposedly in charge of...
isn't producing.
The Federal Government's
AIDS research program is flawed.
So, we're going to have
a small but tasteful little gathering
at the National Institutes of Health
on May 21st.
Storm the NIH.
I called Tony and I said,
"We're coming."
And it was game on.
Every 12 minutes someone dies.
A group calling itself ACT UP
wants changes in AIDS research.
Asking for wider and faster testing
of AIDS fighting drugs.
Here's your money, NIH!
Mounted police
and others wearing rubber gloves
confronted about 1,000 AIDS activists.
They won't test
any of these drugs
that will keep people alive.
No Peptide T, no Compound Q.
Anthony Fauci, I piss on you.
The NIH is lying!
Women with AIDS are dying!
Their decisions for our women,
children, people of color is always no.
Dr. Anthony Fauci
and a lot of other hotshot scientists
are having conferences
deciding research priorities.
We think we should be deciding
the research priorities.
These are the people who know
what's going on
because they're dealing with it every day.
I started to put myself
into their shoes
and finally I realized
what they really wanted
is to be part of the process.
I have a disease.
I'm gonna be dead in X number of months.
You've just given me a plan
that something is gonna happen
in three years.
Thank you very much,
but I'm gonna be dead.
So we need to do a little bit more
about that.
Typical day at the NIH
watching people die!
And I started to feel,
and my staff thought
I was completely nuts...
almost an affinity... to them.
I pulled a banner out of my backpack
and I'm starting to tape it up
and then all of a sudden,
all these cops are lifting each other up.
They're angry that they've been fooled.
And they lower me down into the arms
of all the other cops.
And the commander says,
"Take him through the building."
Halfway down the hall
I see a very familiar sight.
A short man in a white coat.
And, uh, he goes... "Peter?"
And Peter looks me in the eye,
he says, "Tony, I did it. I got arrested.
"I told you I'd get arrested."
And the cop looks at me and says,
"What the shit is going on here?
"Who is this guy? He's your friend?"
Because he knows
this is the Director of the Building
and, like, "Who the hell is this guy
I'm arresting?"
We completely befuddled the police.
Tony understood that
what we were doing was political theater
to move an issue along.
He never stopped being open.
He never said, "The way you treated me
at that demonstration,
"I'm never gonna talk
to you people again."
Instead, it was exactly the opposite.
It's "We need to talk more."
There was a lot of push back
on the part of some of my own staff,
that I was compromising
the scientific process.
You can't have activists involved
in our meetings
where we discuss the design
of a clinical trial.
By that summer,
with the International AIDS Conference
about to happen in San Francisco,
the relationship
between the scientific establishment
and ACT UP was at a breaking point.
About 100 protesters
have already been arrested
at the International AIDS Conference
that began today in San Francisco.
Researchers feel
that they're undervalued.
If they feel that they're gonna be
demonstrated against,
they'll just get out
and do their work in cancer
and Alzheimer's disease and heart,
what have you.
You can beat them down
by this constant harassment.
Larry Kramer called for riots.
It was getting out of hand.
And then the organizers of the conference
tried to placate ACT UP.
They said "If you want to speak,
it's yours."
Exactly 30 days ago,
all of us here in the front
stood up for what we believed in
and vocalized our commitment
on the beautiful grounds
of the National Institutes of Health.
When we make mistakes, what's the fallout?
Some people become offended
and begin to hate ACT UP.
Whereas, when government
or scientific community makes a mistake,
thousands of people can die.
It became patently clear to me
that they were making absolute sense.
It gives me great pleasure
to welcome Dr. Fauci.
It's an honor to have him here.
AIDS in the 1990s has revolutionized
the relationship
between the public and scientists.
The politically charged nature
of the epidemic has put researchers
under an extraordinary degree
of public scrutiny.
They are confronted with the accusation
by some that they are not doing enough
and that they are moving too slowly.
I'm not finished.
The scientific process is often seen
as overly restrictive
and even an impediment to solution.
The most vocal, provocative
and articulate groups among these
are the AIDS Activists.
Some of them are better informed
than many scientists can possibly imagine.
Yet they are sometimes incorrect.
Believe it or not.
However, in the interactions
between physicians, scientists
and activists,
mistakes have been made by both sides.
Activists are mistaken when they assume
that scientists do not care about them.
This is devastating
to a physician scientist
who has devoted years to AIDS research,
particularly when they themselves
see so many of their own patients
suffering and dying.
On the other hand,
scientists cannot dismiss activists
merely on the basis of the fact
that they are not trained scientists.
Activists bring a very special insight
into the disease
that they can actually be helpful
in the way that we design
our scientific approaches.
We must join together,
for together we a formidable force
with a common goal.
We must never lose sight of the fact
that the people whom we serve
are the HIV infected people
throughout the world. Thank you.
During that speech,
I'm saying something
and you have the activists clap.
Then I say something
and the scientists clap.
The beauty of it is that...
at the end of it, everybody was clapping.
The AIDS activists
went from being the adversaries
to actually the people
who were sitting down
at the table with us discussing
what is happening.
And that is a huge shift.
That changed everything.
We were able to redesign
clinical trials for HIV.
Black people, Brown people,
pregnant women,
young people were included.
I'm putting myself at your disposal now.
If I don't have an answer for it...
And your thinking,
has it changed your approach
to research on life threatening disease?
Rather than a real abrupt change,
I think it's an evolution.
You try harder to put yourself
into the position of a patient.
This whole notion of understanding
that we have a value
in those discussions
changed the shape of clinical research
and drug development.
And it went well beyond AIDS.
- What do we want?
- A cure!
- When do we want it?
- Now!
Now it happens in cancer
and it happens in Alzheimer's
and it happens
in all these different disease areas.
Science has realized
you need to include these voices
in the process
because it makes for better science.
And Tony is the one who opened that door.
We're the ones who knocked on that door
and pushed that door
and barged our way in.
But Tony understood the value of it
early on.
The difference now
is that divisiveness
is dominating COVID-19.
I don't see them ever clapping together.
I think we're gonna get through it.
But we're gonna get through it
in spite of this divisiveness
and this politicization.
We're not gonna get through it
because of it.
- Peter!
- Hey. How are you?
Oh, I'm all right.
These fucking dark web people
- are really, really getting bad.
- All right.
They're really, really harassing Chris.
One of them called up...
with violent threats,
like eight times today
on her cell phone
until she figured I've got to just change
my cell phone.
You know, they're harassing
my daughters constantly,
which it really bothers me
more than anything else.
Remind her that almost all of them
are cowards.
- Yeah.
- All just...
Well, that's
what my Secret Service detail says.
- They say... I mean...
- Yeah.
Because they have a lot of experience
with this.
And, you know, they don't want
to make light of it,
but they say that most of them
are just a bunch of fricking cowards.
They want to scare you all.
- Right.
- They want you to back down.
Right.
When COVID hit, at first, it was like,
oh, my God,
give Tony space while he does his thing.
Uh, don't overwhelm him.
Let's try to figure out
what's going wrong.
And then when he became this target,
I just kept checking in.
For me and my sisters
this was really, really new territory.
We heard about what he went through
in the HIV AIDS pandemic.
Like seeing signs, you know,
"Fauci is a murderer."
And I remember asking him, like,
"Is this what it was like?
"Was I just not old enough to understand,
but this is actually what it was like?"
And, you know,
his response is something like,
"You can't even compare the two.
This is so beyond the beyond."
The whole atmosphere...
strains your concept of what normality is.
You know, and just when you think
everything is okay,
I was sitting at my desk
and I opened up a letter
and a puff of powder came up.
It was on my shirt, my tie, my pants,
my hands and my chin.
The first thing I thought of was,
"Holy shit,
why did I open up this letter?"
And then the options started
to crystallize in my mind.
One, it's a hoax.
Two, it's anthrax
and I'm gonna get sick,
but I'm gonna take Cipro
and I'm gonna be okay.
Or three, it's Ricin
and I'm freakin' dead.
Fortunately, it turned out to be a hoax.
My sisters and I
were really worried.
And that was...
It continues to be really disturbing,
really unsettling.
I don't understand the hate
that people have.
And the hate that leads them
to do something
that could hurt somebody
or kill somebody.
I mean, it sort of... reduces my trust
in humanity
in a way that is probably impossible
to measure.
But certainly, I felt it.
I never, for a moment,
thought that I should resign.
I just never thought about it.
I just said to myself...
focus on what you're trying to do.
Is what you're trying to do more important
than all of this other peripheral crap?
If it is, just focus like a laser
and go for it.
Okay.
I just realized that I haven't had
a good night's sleep
in a very, very long time.
I'm waiting until the first person
enters into the phase three trial...
and then,
I'll have a good night's sleep, so.
That will be Moderna, mRNA.
No, no. I know that,
but I'm holding my breath
until that happens.
It must be something psychological.
I keep waking up at 2:30
'til quarter to three in the morning.
Despite this extraordinary divisiveness...
it was very clear we were dealing
with a common enemy
and the common enemy was the virus.
I really do hope that somehow or other
there is a realization
that we can't go on this way,
because it's a lesson that will be,
I think, important for us
to adequately respond
to the next outbreak,
which inevitably will occur.
Maybe not in my lifetime, maybe it will,
but it will occur.
My dad said on TV, on the radio,
to me, to my mom,
to my sisters, like,
"We're gonna get through it."
And he's held that with him
through this whole thing,
when so many people, the whole country,
so many of us have struggled to think,
are we ever gonna get through this thing?
- Are you all set?
- I know.
Somehow he's been able
to hold onto that
because he's lived in times
where it felt like a thing couldn't end.
The search
for an AIDS vaccine...
that hope now has dimmed.
More than a decade into the AIDS epidemic,
we're still nowhere close to a cure.
Since the late '80s, we've seen
pretty splashy reports in the media
about drugs that worked well
in the test tube
and then find out in a few months
that they did not work in people.
This is the bitter new reality of AIDS.
There are more drugs around
to prolong patients' lives,
but their deaths
are more excruciating than ever.
The biomedical research community
is suffering,
for not having solved the problem.
Our country says,
"Why can't you guys do this?"
It is conceivable
that we will never get a vaccine.
I think we have to face that reality.
People sometimes hesitate
to talk about that
because it gets taken out of context
and people say well, they're giving up.
No-one is giving up.
There were a number of studies
that were going on
that were funded by my institute.
We had gradual progress...
but never the home run.
And then, in 1996,
there are a couple of studies
that incorporated protease inhibitors
as one of three drugs
that were given in combination.
On Close Up this morning,
reports of possible new treatments
for AIDS.
AIDS drugs known
as protease inhibitors
may actually eliminate the AIDS virus
in human tissue.
I'd had the pneumonias
and I was getting skinnier...
and I didn't have much fight left in me.
And I got down here with NIH in 1995
and I was one of the first people
in the country
that was given the cocktail.
And seven days later,
my numbers had started to change.
And my T cells started to rise and...
my viral burden started to go down.
I just need a second. Uh...
Um...
That was the moment that changed my life.
I started getting better.
Immune systems are restoring
back to normalcy,
the virus is disappearing.
It's gotten to levels so low,
it can't even be found.
It's called the AIDS cocktail.
And the success of the cocktail
is the first real sign
that the AIDS epidemic
may not be invincible.
It really was, like,
the most amazing thing
to go from a physician
to terminally ill patients
to a physician who could prevent people
from dying.
It's the best we've seen
thus far with any drugs.
The effects are profound.
I'm certain they're going to be translated
into positive clinical benefits.
I no longer feel
as though I'm dying, I no longer crave it.
I don't have contingency plans
to end my life.
I'm not in that mode at all.
I'm back among the living.
I'm a grandmother,
but that's only one grandchild.
I still have two other children
that don't have children.
You know, I want a house full.
And if I keep taking my medicine
I'm gonna be here
to rock every single one of them
on my lap.
It's nice to have new things
down the road to look forward to.
Yeah, I feel like I'm 16 again,
it's great.
Every birthday since I've been 35...
there isn't one birthday, not one,
that I don't thank him
for what he has done for me.
My dad turned 80 this year
and it was the first birthday,
Christmas Eve, Christmas
that we weren't all together.
Since I was a little kid,
I've often taken the role of...
you know, telling him,
like, "You have to take a break.
"You have to slow down.
You have to take care of yourself."
But I saw that as long
as the COVID pandemic
was happening, he was gonna be all in.
So, I tried to be there for him
in a different kind of way from afar.
Checking in with him, calling him,
sending him text messages of birds,
sending him pictures of my dog.
Something to keep him going.
Right now,
what I'm going through...
is kind of like a diabolical repeat...
of what went on
back when they were children growing up.
But now they're adults
and they see what I'm going through...
and what Chris is going through.
And... they are just amazingly supportive
and proud.
- Hi, Ali.
- Hey, Ali, babe. Hey, Jane.
- Megan's there too.
- Hey, Megan D.
Hi, sweet thing. I love you.
- I love you too.
- Take care.
I wish you guys were here.
As much as I've given my dad
a hard time my whole life,
I'm so grateful to see an example
of what it means
to stay committed to who you are
and stay committed to what you believe in.
With HIV AIDS,
when we finally nailed down
the triple combination
that brought down the level of virus
to below detectable,
it was close to euphoria.
People were going back
to what turned out to be
a semi normal existence.
But that then shined a bright light
on the disparity
between the developed world
and the developing world.
Inequality raises its head
in many different ways in our world.
HIV AIDS, it was very clear...
we could get those pills
for those people or not.
What would that cost to give patients
the drugs that they need?
Six hundred US dollars per month.
And a man like this,
how much would he make a month?
Maybe five, ten dollars.
The perspective was,
we'll never be able to do that in Africa,
for all sorts of crazy reasons.
Not enough money,
people wouldn't take medications,
it's impossible.
These drugs have to be administered
during a certain sequence
at a time during the day
and when you say,
"Take it at ten o'clock."
People will say,
"What do you mean by ten o'clock?"
If you've traveled rural Africa,
you know this.
This is not a criticism,
just a different world.
People do not know
what watches and clocks are.
They do not use Western means
for telling the time. They use the sun.
Early in my Administration,
Condi Rice said "Mr. President,
"are you aware there's a pandemic
destroying an entire generation of people
in the continent of Africa?"
I said,
"We need to do something about it."
People in my Administration
whose judgment I trust said, you know,
"Unleash Fauci."
Tony Fauci doesn't come
in the Oval Office and say,
"I'm gonna make you look good
politically."
He's not a politician.
Tony Fauci says,
"I think we can solve this problem.
"Here are the facts,
and here's my recommendation
for a way forward."
So, President Bush told me,
"Go to Africa
and scout it out.
See if there's something that we can do."
In Uganda, what we saw was,
I believe,
what many people think
would not be able to be effected...
and that is groups of volunteers
on motorcycles and jeeps
going into the very, very rural areas,
into the homes of people
and delivering drugs.
I remember going
into a thatched hut.
"How are you doing?" "Fine."
"You're taking your medicines?"
"Yes, I'm taking them very regularly."
"You understand
what the medicine is doing?"
"Yes, it's blocking the virus
that's killing my CD4 cells."
Like, what?
All of this stuff that people were saying,
that Africans don't have
whatever it is it takes
to understand the importance
of taking their drug regularly
was clearly, you know,
unmitigated bullshit.
We put together a model
that was a phenomenally expanded version
of what Peter Mugyenyi was already doing.
He had people delivering drugs
that weren't even nurses
on motorcycles into the bush.
You know, hundreds of miles away.
And people would take the drug.
They knew what they were doing.
You could get their viral load down.
All you needed to do
was to give them the drugs.
So, I put forth to the president
a 15 billion dollar program called PEPFAR.
The President's Emergency Plan
For AIDS Relief.
I ask the Congress to commit
15 billion dollars
over the next five years,
including nearly ten billion dollars
in new money
to turn the tide against AIDS
in the most afflicted nations of Africa
and the Caribbean.
Fifteen billion dollars. Boom!
It was just the most magnificent moment,
uh, because I knew what that really meant.
We're talking
about preventing seven million infections.
In other words, seven million people
who otherwise would have gotten infected
and with no therapy would have died.
PEPFAR was a huge milestone,
this, you know,
miraculous AIDS intervention
that... continues to save
tens of millions of lives.
It's the largest
bilateral program in health
ever created anywhere
and Tony was an early architect of it
and it changed the world.
Tony's been made the size
of the tasks he takes on.
He becomes the size of the challenge
he faces each time.
AIDS is one of the most
devastating scourges in human history.
The US President's Emergency Plan
For AIDS Relief has done heroic work
in making AIDS drugs available
to those who need them.
Striving for universal access
to AIDS therapies
is a public health and moral imperative
that should be embraced by all.
I mean that, to me, is, you know,
one of the great success stories
in all of medicine.
When you have a global pandemic,
you absolutely need a global solution.
To think that you can take care
of yourself
without taking care
of the rest of the world is just folly.
What the NIH has accomplished,
can accomplish and will accomplish,
to me, that's the embodiment
of the American spirit.
The experience that you can do anything
if you put your mind to it, anything.
- Hi, Dr. Azar.
- Hi, guys.
- Hi, Dr. Fauci.
- These are out health care workers.
- Good morning, Dr. Fauci.
- How are you doing?
- Good. How are you?
- And one behind us here.
I'm good.
And I have to take one with you.
My daughter will kill me if I don't.
Having lived through
this extraordinary, historic experience,
it just confirms it's always
the sustained investment in science
that rises to the occasion.
It is fitting that
we gather here today on NIH campus
to administer vaccines
designed to battle COVID-19.
The young people in medicine
really need to understand
what is possible
when the biomedical research community
of this country and the world
decides that they're going after a problem
in a very serious way.
Next we have Dr. Tony Fauci.
Many in our nation are saying
if Dr. Fauci gets the vaccine,
I'm gonna get the vaccine.
So, tell us a little bit
why it's important?
Well, to me,
it's important for two reasons.
One is that I'm an attending
physician here on the staff
at the National Institutes
of Health Clinical Center
and so I do see patients.
But, as important, or more important,
is as a symbol to the rest of the country
that I feel extreme confidence
in the safety and the efficacy
of this vaccine
and I want to encourage everyone
who has the opportunity
to get vaccinated so that we can have
a veil of protection over this country
that would end this pandemic.
Thank you, Dr. Fauci
for coming today.
- Any last minute questions, concerns?
- No.
Thank you so much.
Bye, Dr. Fauci.
Dr. Fauci, you know him well,
getting this vaccine,
saying how important it is
to show the American people it is safe.
What a moment
for the man who played such a role
in developing this vaccine,
to get the vaccine himself.
Excellent.
In March 2020,
when we were first envisioning vaccines
for this coronavirus,
nobody thought that we would have them
by the end of the year.
How do you feel, Tony?
Nothing. Feeling good.
- Feeling good.
- Excellent.
There have been many times
in previous administrations
where people have not wanted
to fund the NIH quite as much
because they thought, "well,
this is just a bunch of scientists
doing lab work.
How does that help the regular person?"
This is how it helps the regular person.
Thank you.
A public servant is somebody
who gives their skill,
their intellect, their experience
to the people of the United States.
You don't do it because you want
to make money,
you don't do it for the glory.
You do it because you care.
The two most devastating pandemics
in the last 100 years
are, sort of, like bookends on my career
and my life.
When you're involved in a race
to stop a horrible disease...
you always feel you're not doing things
quickly enough... or well enough.
You know, it just reminds me so much
of when we were struggling
to develop effective therapies for HIV.
If we had just gotten it
a day earlier, a week earlier,
a month earlier...
these number of people
would not have died.
One of the most mysterious aspects
of our universe
is how viruses have transformed
our civilization.
There was a Nobel Prize-winning
bacteriologist
named Joshua Lederberg, who says,
"It's a never-ending battle
"between viruses'
spectacular genetic capability,
"and our wits."
As someone at my age
and my stage in life,
it's natural to look ahead and say,
"What are my children
gonna be faced with?"
And the one thing I can hope for...
really hope for,
is that emerging infections
don't inevitably become pandemics.
I am optimistic that the lessons
that we've learned
will prevent that from happening.
I hope that if historians look back...
if they ever would wanna look back...
at what I've done, and my life.
Maybe somebody says,
"Hey, that guy was pretty good."