All third-class passengers...
with a forward berth...
this way please! This queue!
It's a big boat?
Daddy, it's a ship.
You're right.
I don't see what all
the fuss is about.
It doesn't look any bigger
than the Mauretania.
You can be blasé
about some things, Rose...
but not about Titanic.
It's over 100 feet longer
than Mauretania...
and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is far too
difficult to impress, Ruth.
So this is the ship they
say is unsinkable.
It is unsinkable.
God Himself
could not sink this ship...
What?!
You have to check your baggage
through the main terminal.
It's round that way, sir.
I put my faith in you good sir.
Now kindly see my man.
Yes sir. It's my pleasure, sir.
If I can do anything at all...
Yes, right.
All the trunks from
that car there.
12 from here.
And the safe,
to the parlor suite...
rooms B-52, 54, 56.
Ladies...
we better hurry.
Come along.
- My coat?
- I have it, miss.
All third-class passengers
queue here for health inspection.
- Welcome aboard, ma'am.
- Welcome to Titanic.
It was the ship of dreams...
to everyone else.
To me. It was a slave ship...
taking me back to
America in chains.
Outwardly, I was everything
a well brought up girl should be.
Inside, I was screaming.
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing,
you got nothing to lose.
Sven?
All right, moment of truth.
Someone's life is
about to change.
Fabrizio?
Niente.
Olaf?
Nothing.
Sven?
2 pair.
I'm sorry, Fabrizio.
I'm sorry...
you're not gonna see
your mom again for a...
Long time...
'cause we're going to America.
Full house, boys!
Come on.
I'm going home!
I'm going home.
I go to America!
No, mate.
Titanic go to America,
in 5 minutes.
Shit. Fabri. Come on.
Come on, here. Here.
We're riding in high style now!
We're a couple of
regular swells.
We're practically
goddamn royalty...
ragazzo mio.
You see? Is my destino.
Like I told you...
I go to America to
be millionaire.
You are pazzo.
Maybe, but I've
got the tickets.
Come on, I thought
you were fast.
Aspetta!
Wait! Wait!
Hey, wait!
We're passengers!
Have you been through
the inspection queue?
Of course.
Anyway, we don't have any lice.
We're Americans. Both of us.
Right.
Come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons
of bitches in the world.
You know that?
Good-bye!
You know somebody?
Of course not.
That's not the point.
Good-bye! I'll miss you!
Good-bye!
I will never forget you!
Come with me,
darling. Let's go.
G-60.
G-60. G-60.
Excuse me, ma'am.
G-60.
Oh, right here.
Hey, how you doing?
Jack. Nice to meet you.
Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing?
Who says you get top bunk?
This is your private
promenade deck, sir.
Will you be requiring anything?
Excuse me.
- This one?
- No.
It had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of
them out, miss?
Yes. We need a little
color in this room.
Put in there. In the wardrobe.
God, not those finger
paintings again.
They certainly were a
waste of money.
The difference between
Cal's taste in art...
and mine is that I have some.
They're fascinating.
Like being inside a dream
or something.
There's truth but no logic.
- What's the artist's name?
- Something Picasso.
Something Picasso.
He won't amount to a thing.
He won't, trust me.
- Let's put the Degas in the bedroom.
- At least they were cheap.
Put it in the wardrobe.
At Cherbourg, a woman came aboard
named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her
the Unsinkable Molly Brown.
Well, I wasn't about to
wait all day for you, sonny.
Here, if you think
you can manage.
Her husband had struck gold
someplace out west.
And she was what Mother
called "new money."
By the next afternoon...
we were steaming west
from the coast of Ireland...
with nothing out ahead
of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr. Murdoch.
Let's stretch her legs.
Yes sir.
All ahead full, Mr. Moody.
Very good, sir.
All ahead full.
All ahead full!
Come on lads, step lively!
All right! Let's stoke
her right up!
We go full ahead!
Come on, put your
backs into it!
21 knots, sir.
Hey, look, look, look!
See it?
There's another one! See him?
Look at that one!
Look at him jump!
I can see the Statue
of Liberty already.
Very small, of course.
I'm the king of the world!
She is the largest moving object
ever made by the hand of man...
in all history.
And our master shipbuilder,
Mr. Andrews here...
designed her from the
keel plates up.
I may have knocked
her together, but...
the idea was Mr. Ismay's.
He envisioned a steamer
so grand in scale...
and so luxurious in...
its appointments...
that its supremacy
would never be challenged.
And here she is.
- Willed into solid reality.
- Hear, hear.
I'll have the salmon.
You know I don't
like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb.
Rare, with very
little mint sauce.
You like lamb, right sweet pea?
You gonna cut her meat
for her too there, Cal?
Hey, who thought of
the name Titanic?
Was it you, Bruce?
Yes, actually.
I wanted to convey sheer size.
And size means stability...
luxury, and above
all, strength.
Do you know of
Dr. Freud, Mr. Ismay?
His ideas about the male preoccupation with
size might be of particular interest to you.
What's gotten into you?
Excuse me.
I do apologize.
She's a pistol, Cal.
Hope you can handle her.
Well, I may have to start minding what she
reads from now on, won't I, Mrs. Brown?
Freud? Who is he?
Is he a passenger?
The ship is nice?
Yeah. It's an Irish ship.
Is English, no?
No, it was built in Ireland.
15,000 Irishmen
built this ship.
Solid as a rock.
Big Irish hands.
That's typical.
First-class dogs
come down here to take a shite.
Lets us know where we rank
in the scheme of things.
Like we could forget?
I'm Tommy Ryan.
- Jack Dawson.
- Fabrizio.
Do you make any money
with your drawings?
Forget it, boyo.
You'd as like have angels fly out of
your arse as get next to...
the likes of her.
I saw my whole life
as if I'd already lived it.
An endless parade
of parties and cotillions...
yachts and polo matches.
Always the same narrow people,
the same mindless chatter.
I felt like I was standing
at a great precipice...
with no one to pull me back.
No one who cared...
or even noticed.
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on.
Just give me your hand.
I'll pull you back over.
No! Stay where you are.
I mean it.
I'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no I won't?
Don't presume to tell me
what I will and will not do.
You don't know me.
Well, you would have done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
I can't.
I'm involved now.
You let go, and I'm going to have
to jump in there after you.
Don't be absurd.
- You'll be killed.
- I'm a good swimmer.
The fall alone will kill you.
It would hurt. I'm not
saying it wouldn't.
Tell you the truth...
I'm a lot more concerned
about that water being so cold.
How cold?
Freezing.
Maybe a couple degrees over.
You ever...
ever been to Wisconsin?
What?
Well, they have some of
the coldest winters around.
I grew up there,
near Chippewa Falls.
I remember when I was a kid,
me and my father, we went ice fishing...
out on Lake Wissota.
Ice fishing is, you know, where you...
I know what ice fishing is!
Sorry.
You just seem like, you know,
kind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, I...
fell through some thin ice.
And I'm telling you...
water that cold,
like right down there...
it hits you like 1000 knives
stabbing you all over your body.
You can't breathe.
You can't think. Least not about
anything but the pain.
Which is why I'm not looking
forward to jumping in there after you.
Like I said...
I don't have a choice.
I guess I'm kind of hoping you'll
come back over the rail and...
and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says but...
with all due respect, miss...
I'm not the one hanging off
the back of a ship here.
Come on.
Come on, give me your hand.
You don't want to do this.
I'm Jack Dawson.
Rose DeWitt Bukater.
I'll have to get you to
write that one down.
Come on.
I got you.
Help, please!
Help!
- Please, help me!
- Listen. Listen to me.
Listen. Listen to me.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on!
Come on.
That's right.
You can do it.
I got you.
What's all this?
You stand back and...
don't move an inch!
Fetch the Master at Arms.
This is completely unacceptable!
What made you think that you could
put your hands on my fiancée?!
Look at me, you filth!
Cal.
What do you think
you were doing?
Cal, stop. It was an accident.
An accident?
It was.
Stupid, really.
I was leaning over and I slipped.
I was leaning far over
to see the...
The...
- Propellers?
- Propellers, and I slipped.
And I would have gone
overboard but Mr. Dawson here...
saved me. And almost
went over himself.
You wanted to see the...
She wanted to see the propellers.
Like I said, women and
machinery do not mix.
Was that the way of it?
Yeah. Yeah, that
was pretty much it.
Well, the boy's a hero then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So, it's all's well and back
to our brandy, eh?
Look at you. You must be freezing.
Let's get you inside.
Perhaps a little something
for the boy?
Of course.
Mr. Lovejoy,
I think a 20 should do it.
Is that the going rate
for saving the woman you love?
Rose is displeased.
What to do?
I know.
Perhaps you could join us for
dinner tomorrow evening...
to regale our group...
with your heroic tale.
Sure. Count me in.
Good. It's settled then.
This should be interesting.
Can I bum a smoke?
You'll want to tie those.
It's interesting...
the young lady slipped
so suddenly...
and you still had time to remove
your jacket and your shoes.
I know you've been melancholy.
I don't pretend to know why.
I intended to save this...
until the engagement
gala next week...
but, I thought...
tonight.
Good gracious.
Perhaps as a reminder
of my feelings for you.
- Is it a...
- Diamond. Yes.
56 carats to be exact.
It was worn by Louis XVI.
And they called
it Le Coeur de la Mer.
- The Heart of the Ocean.
- The Heart of the Ocean. Yes.
It's overwhelming.
Well, it's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there's
nothing I couldn't give you.
There's nothing I'd deny you...
if you would not deny me.
Open your heart to me, Rose.
Well, I've been on my own since
I was 15, since my folks died.
And I had no brothers or sisters or
close kin in that part of the country...
so I lit on out of there and I
haven't been back since.
You could just call me a
tumbleweed blowing in the wind.
Well, Rose, we've walked about a mile
around this boat deck and...
chewed over how great the weather's
been and how I grew up...
but I reckon that's not why
you came to talk to me, is it?
- Mr. Dawson, I...
- Jack.
Jack.
I want to thank you
for what you did.
Not just for pulling me back,
but for your discretion.
You're welcome.
Look.
I know what you
must be thinking.
Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery?
No.
No, that's not what I was thinking.
What I was thinking was...
what could have happened to this girl
to make her think she had no way out?
Well I...
It was everything.
It was my whole world and...
all the people in it.
And the inertia of my life,
plunging ahead and me...
powerless to stop it.
God, look at that thing.
You would have gone
straight to the bottom.
500 invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society will be there.
And all the while I feel I'm...
standing in the middle
of a crowded room...
screaming at the
top of my lungs...
and no one even looks up.
Do you love him?
Pardon me?
You're being very rude. You
shouldn't be asking me this.
Well, it's a simple question.
Do you love the guy or not?
This is not a suitable conversation.
Why can't you just
answer the question?
This is absurd.
You don't know me
and I don't know you...
and we are not having this
conversation at all. You are rude...
and uncouth and presumptuous
and I am leaving now...
Jack. Mr. Dawson.
It's been a pleasure.
I sought you out to thank you
and now I have thanked you.
And you've insulted me.
Well, you deserved it.
- Right.
I thought you were leaving.
I am.
You are so annoying.
Wait.
I don't have to leave. This is
my part of the ship. You leave.
Well, well, well.
Now who's being rude?
What is this stupid thing
you're carrying around?
So, what are you,
an artist or something?
These are rather good.
They're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
They didn't think too
much of them in old Paree.
Paris?
You do get around for a p...
Well, a... a
person of limited means.
Go on. A poor guy. You can say it.
Well, well, well.
And these were drawn from life?
Well, that's one of the
good things about Paris.
Lots of girls are willing
to take their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well.
She had beautiful
hands, you see?
I think you must have
had a love affair with her.
No, no, no.
Just with her hands.
She was a
one-legged prostitute.
See?
She had a good
sense of humor though.
Oh, and this lady...
She used to sit at this bar every night...
wearing every piece
of jewelry she owned...
just waiting for
her long, lost love.
We called her Madame Bijoux.
See, her clothes are all moth-eaten.
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
You see people.
I see you.
And?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university
is to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Look, here comes that
vulgar Brown woman.
Quickly, get up before
she sits with us.
Hello, girls. I was hoping
I'd catch you at tea.
We're awfully sorry,
you missed it.
The Countess and I were just
off to take the air on the boat deck.
What a lovely idea.
I need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
So, you've not yet lit the
last four boilers?
No, I don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic.
Now, I want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them
something new to print.
This maiden voyage
of Titanic must...
make headlines.
Mr. Ismay, I would prefer
not to push the engines...
until they've been properly run in.
Of course I'm just a passenger.
I leave it to your good offices
to decide what's best.
But what a glorious end
to your final crossing...
if we were to get into New York
on Tuesday night...
and surprise them all.
Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, E. J?
Good man.
After that, I worked
on a squid boat in Monterey...
then I went to Los Angeles to the...
Santa Monica pier
and did portraits for 10 cents each.
Why can't I be like you?
Just head out for the horizon
whenever I feel like it.
Say we'll go there
sometime, to that pier...
only if we just talk about it.
No, we'll do it. We'll drink cheap beer.
Ride on the roller coaster
till we throw up.
We'll ride horses on the
beach, in the surf.
But you have to do it like a real cowboy.
No sidesaddle stuff.
You mean with one leg on each side?
Can you show me?
Sure, if you like.
Teach me to ride like a man.
Chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man.
You didn't learn in finishing school?
No.
Come on, I'll show you.
I'll show you how.
Jack! No, Jack, no. Wait.
I couldn't possibly, Jack.
Watch closely.
That's disgusting.
Your turn.
That was pitiful.
You really have to hawk it back.
Get some leverage.
Use your arms. Arc your neck.
You see the range on that thing?
Okay, go.
That was better. You have to work on it.
Really try to hawk it up.
Mother.
May I introduce Jack Dawson?
Charmed, I'm sure.
The others were gracious and curious
about the man who'd saved my life.
But my mother looked at him like an insect.
A dangerous insect
which must be squashed quickly.
Sounds like you're a good man
to have around in a sticky spot.
Why do they always insist on announcing
dinner like a damn cavalry charge?
Shall we go dress, Mother?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Son?
Son!
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Not really.
You're about to go into the snake pit.
What are you going to wear?
I figured. Come on.
I was right. You and my son
are just about the same size.
Pretty close.
You shine up like a new penny.
Good evening, sir.
Thousands of tons of Hockley steel
are in this ship.
- Which part?
- All the right ones.
Then you're accountable
if there's a problem. Where's Rose?
She'll be along.
There is the Countess.
I saw that in a nickelodeon
and always wanted to do it.
Darling...
surely you remember Mr. Dawson.
It's amazing.
You could almost pass for a gentleman.
Almost.
This is extraordinary.
This is a remarkable voyage.
- Mad.
- Completely lunatic.
There's the Countess of Rothes.
That's John Jacob Astor...
the richest man on board.
His little wifey, Madeleine,
is my age and in a delicate condition.
See how she tries to hide it.
Quite the scandal.
Benjamin Guggenheim and his mistress,
Madame Aubert. Mrs. Guggenheim...
is at home with the children, of course.
And over here...
Sir Cosmo and Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie,
among her many talents.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations. She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
Escort a lady to dinner?
Certainly.
Sweet pea, sweet pea.
Ain't nothing to it.
They love money. Pretend like you own
a gold mine and you're in the club.
Hey, Astor.
Hello, Molly. Nice to see you.
J.J., Madeleine,
I'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
Well, Jack...
are you of the Boston Dawsons?
No, the Chippewa Falls Dawsons, actually.
Oh, yes.
He must have been nervous.
But he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them.
Heir to a rail road fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously,
but still a member of the club.
Mother. Of course.
Could always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations in steerage,
Mr. Dawson. I hear they're quite good.
The best I've seen, ma'am. Hardly any rats.
Mr. Dawson is joining us from third class.
He was of help to my fiancée last night.
It happens Mr. Dawson
is quite a fine artist.
He showed me some of his work today.
Rose and I differ in our definition of fine art.
Not to impugn your work, sir.
Are all these mine?
Start from the outside and work in.
He knows every rivet in her.
Your ship is a wonder, Mr. Andrews.
Thank you, Rose.
How do you take your caviar, sir?
No caviar for me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
Where exactly do you live, Mr. Dawson?
Right now, my address is the RMS Titanic.
After that, I'm on God's good humor.
How do you have means to travel?
I work my way from place to place.
Tramp steamers and such.
I won my ticket on Titanic
at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
A real man makes his own luck.
Right, Dawson?
And you find
that sort of rootless existence appealing?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
I've got everything I need
right here with me.
I have air in my lungs
and blank sheets of paper.
I love waking up, not knowing
what will happen or who I'll meet.
Where I'll wind up.
One night I'm sleeping under a bridge...
now I'm on the grandest ship
in the world, with you fine people.
I'll take more of that.
Life's a gift. I don't
intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand you'll get dealt.
You take life as it comes at you.
Here, Cal.
Make each day count.
Well said, Jack.
Hear, hear.
To making it count.
Bravo.
But Mr. Brown didn't know
I'd hidden the money in the stove.
He comes home drunk as a pig celebrating
and lights a fire.
Next is brandy in the smoking room.
Join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
Now they retreat to congratulate each
other on being masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for your company.
May I escort you to the cabin?
No, I'll stay here.
Here, Molly.
Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay with the women.
No, thanks. I have to head back.
That's best. It'll be all business and politics.
Wouldn't interest you.
But Dawson, good of you to come.
Must you go?
Time for me to row with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
Want to go to a real party?
Is okay I put my hand here?
I can't understand you.
I'm going to dance with her now.
Come on.
Come on. Come with me.
Jack. Jack, wait.
I can't do this.
We'll have to get a bit closer.
Like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
- I don't know the steps.
- Me, either. Just go with it.
Don't think.
Wait! Jack! Wait! Stop, Jack!
What? Wait!
Jack, no.
Beyond the jurisdiction
of the Sherman Act.
That's what Rockefeller said...
Supreme Court didn't swallow it.
What? You think
a first-class girl can't drink?
Get out of here.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Two out of three.
So...
you think you're tough?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack. Hold it up.
Jesus!
You okay?
I haven't done that in years.
Come on, lads. Give it all you got.
Let's go.
Coffee, sir?
You didn't come to me last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below deck
were no doubt exhausting.
I see you had
that undertaker of a manservant follow me.
You will never behave like that again.
I'm not one of your mill foremen
who you can command.
I'm your fiancée.
My fiancée. My fiancée!
Yes, you are! And my wife!
My wife in practice,
if not yet by law, so you will honor me!
You will honor me the way
a wife honors her husband.
Because I will not be made a fool of.
Is this in any way unclear?
No.
Good. Excuse me.
Oh, Miss Rose.
We had a little accident.
- That's all right.
- I'm sorry.
Let me help you.
It's all right, miss.
Tea, Trudy.
You're not to see that boy again.
You understand?
Rose, I forbid it.
Stop it, Mother.
You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Of course I know.
You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing but a legacy
of bad debts hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card we have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley.
It will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on me?
Why are you being so selfish?
I'm being selfish?
Do you want to see me
working as a seamstress?
Is that what you want?
To see our fine things sold at auction?
Our memories scattered?
It's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Protect them by Thy guiding hand
From every peril on the land
O, spirit whom the Father sent
To spread abroad the firmament
O, wind of heaven, by Thy might
Save all who dare the eagle's flight
And keep them by Thy watchful care...
Hello, Mr. Andrews.
I need to talk to someone.
You're not supposed to be in here.
I was here last night, remember?
No. Now please turn around.
He'll tell you. I just need to talk...
Mr. Hockley and Mrs. DeWitt Bukater...
are still appreciative
of your assistance.
They asked me
to give you this in gratitude...
I don't want your money.
And remind you you are
in third class and your presence here...
is no longer appropriate.
Let me speak to Rose.
Gentlemen, please see Mr. Dawson
returns to where he belongs...
and that he stays there?
Yes, sir.
Come along, you.
Hear us when we cry to Thee
For those in peril on the sea
Why are there two steering wheels?
We use this one near shore.
Excuse me, sir.
Another ice warning, from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Not to worry.
Quite normal for this time of year.
In fact, we're speeding up.
I've ordered the last boilers lit.
Okay, son, wind it up tight
like I showed you. That's right.
Okay, now let it go.
- It was good, wasn't it?
- Quite nice. That's excellent.
Mr. Andrews... Forgive me.
I did the sum in my head...
and with the number of lifeboats
times the capacity you mentioned...
Forgive me, but it seems that there are
not enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you?
In fact, I put in these new
type davits...
which can take an extra row
of boats inside this one.
But it was thought, by some...
the deck would look
too cluttered.
So, I was overruled.
It's a waste of deck space
as it is on an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
I have built you a good ship,
strong and true.
She's all the lifeboat
you need.
Just keep heading aft. The next
stop will be the engine room.
Jack, this is impossible.
I can't see you.
- I need to talk to you.
- No, Jack. No.
Jack. I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose...
you're no picnic. All right?
You're a spoiled little brat even.
But under that, you're the
most amazingly, astounding...
wonderful girl...
woman, that I've ever known.
Jack, I...
No, let me try and get
this out. You're ama...
I'm not an idiot.
I know how the world works.
I've got ten bucks
in my pocket.
I have nothing to offer
you and I know that.
I understand.
But I'm too involved now.
You jump, I jump. Remember?
I can't turn away without
knowing you'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine. Really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They've got you trapped, Rose.
And you're gonna die if you
don't break free.
Maybe not right away...
because you're strong...
but sooner or later that
fire that I love about you, Rose...
that fire is gonna burn out.
It's not up to you
to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
I'm going back.
Leave me alone.
Tell Lucile about the disaster
you had with the stationers.
Well, of course the invitations
had to be sent back, twice.
Oh, my dear.
And the dreadful
bridesmaids' gowns.
Let me tell you what an
odyssey that has been.
Rose decided she
wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color.
So, she did it only to spite me.
If only you'd come to
me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs in
La Mode Illustrée.
They were for the trousseau of the Duchess
of Marlborough's youngest daughter.
They were quite charming.
But, I think you'll agree,
my dear, that together...
we've created something
of a phoenix from the ashes.
Hello, Jack.
I changed my mind.
They said you might be up here.
Give me your hand.
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Now, step up.
Now, hold onto the railing.
Keep your eyes closed.
Don't peek.
I'm not.
Now, step up onto the rail.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
All right...
open your eyes.
I'm flying.
Jack.
Come, Josephine, in my
flying machine. Going up...
she goes. Up she goes.
That was the last time
Titanic ever saw daylight.
We're up to dusk the
night of the sinking.
6 hours to go.
Incredible. There's Smith and
he's standing there and...
he's got the iceberg warning
in his fucking hand...
excuse me... his hand,
and he's ordering more speed.
26 years of experience
working against him.
He figures anything big
enough to sink, the ship...
they're gonna see in time to turn.
But the ship's too big
with too small a rudder.
Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
It's quite proper, I assure you.
This is the sitting room.
- Will this light do?
- What?
Don't artists need good light?
That is true, but I'm not
used to working in...
such horrible conditions.
Monet!
- Do you know his work?
- Of course.
Look at his use of color here.
Isn't he great?
I know. It's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting
this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him
any time soon?
Not as long as the cigars
and brandy hold out.
That's nice.
What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond.
A very rare diamond.
Jack, I want you to draw me
like one of your French girls.
Wearing this.
All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing I need is another picture
of me looking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer...
I expect to get what I want.
Over on the bed... the couch.
Come. Lie down.
- Tell me when it looks right.
- Keep that.
Put your arm back
the way it was.
Put that other arm up,
that hand right by your face there.
Right.
Now, head down.
Eyes to me. Keep them on me.
And try to stay still.
So serious.
I believe you are blushing,
Mr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine
Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
- Just relax your face.
- Sorry.
No laughing.
My heart was pounding
the whole time.
It was the most erotic
moment of my life...
up until then, at least.
So what happened next?
You mean, did we do it?
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Will you put this
back in the safe for me?
Gentlemen, would you excuse me.
None of the stewards
have seen her.
This is absurd. It's a ship.
There's only so many
places she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
- Clear.
- Yes.
I don't think I've ever
seen such a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath of wind.
It will make the bergs
harder to see...
with no breaking
water at the base.
Well, I'm off.
Maintain speed and
heading, Mr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold.
You look nice.
Miss Rose?
My drawings!
Come on!
Wait, wait, wait!
- Go. Go. Down, down.
- Take us down, quickly. Quickly!
Bye.
Sorry.
- Keep going.
- Thank you, I've got it.
Pretty tough for
a valet, this fella.
Seems more like a cop.
I think he was.
- Oh, shit.
- Go!
No, over here!
Quick!
Now what?
What?
More coal for number one, mate.
Hold up? What are you two
doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here.
It could be dangerous!
Carry on!
Don't mind us. You're
doing a great job!
Keep up the good work!
Look at what we have here?
Thank you.
Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
It's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice, you know.
When it's near.
Bollocks!
Well, I can, all right?
Did you ever find those
binoculars for the lookouts?
Haven't seen them
since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds.
Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
- They ran down there.
- Right.
Anything missing?
I have a better idea.
Got you!
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see them?
When the ship docks...
I'm getting off with you.
This is crazy.
I know. It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
Here, look at this.
Look at that, would you?
They're warmer than we are.
If that's what it takes for us to get warm,
I'd rather not.
Bugger me!
Pick up, you bastards!
Is anyone there?!
What do you see?
Iceberg, right ahead!
Thank you.
Iceberg ahead!
Hard a' starboard!
Turn! Turn! Smartly!
Full astern!
Hard over.
Helm's hard over, sir.
Go, lads, go!
Bring that steam down! Bring it down!
Shut all the dampers! Shut them!
Hold it.
Hold it!
Now! Engage reversing engine!
Why ain't they turning?
Is it hard over?!
It is, sir. Hard over.
Come on, come on, come on. Turn.
Yes.
It's going to hit!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus!
Hard to port!
Get back!
Let's go!
They're closing the doors! Get out!
Get out the door! Go!
Go! Come on, lads! Go, lads, go!
Go! Go!
Out! Out!
Oh, my God.
That was a close shave.
Smell ice, can you? Bleedin' Christ!
Note the time. Enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard,
but it was too close.
I tried to port round it, but...
- Close the watertight doors.
- They're closed, sir.
All stop.
Have the carpenter sound the ship.
Come on, let's get the hell out of here!
Why have the engines stopped?
I felt a shudder.
Not to worry. We threw a propeller blade.
That's the shudder you felt.
Do you need anything?
No, thank you.
There's talk of an iceberg.
I don't see anything. Do you?
If this is where the rats
are going, I am, too.
- You.
- There is no emergency.
- There is. I've been robbed.
- Get the Master at Arms.
Now, you moron!
Did I miss the fun?
- Did you see what happened?
- No. I guess it hit over there.
Boiler room six is flooded eight feet
and the mail hold is worse.
- Can you shore up?
- Not unless the pumps get ahead.
- Have you seen the mail hold?
- It's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
I think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
I want the room photographed.
We've been looking for you, miss.
Here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed.
Two things dear to me have disappeared.
Now that one is back,
I know where to find the other. Search him.
- Take your coat off.
- Now what?
What are you doing?
We're in the middle of an emergency.
- Is this it?
- That's it.
This is horseshit!
Don't you believe it.
- He couldn't have.
- Easy enough for a professional.
I was with him the entire time.
Perhaps he did it while you were putting
your clothes back on, dear.
Real slick. They put it in my pocket.
- Shut up.
- It isn't even your pocket.
"Property of A.L. Ryerson."
That was reported stolen.
I just borrowed it.
Oh, we have an honest thief.
You know I didn't do this, Rose.
Don't believe them. You know it.
Let's go, son.
You know I didn't do it!
There's a good lad. Come on.
You know I didn't do it! You know me!
This is most unfortunate, Captain.
Water fourteen feet above the keel
in ten minutes...
in the forepeak,
all three holds and boiler room six.
That's right.
When can we get underway?
That's five compartments.
She can float with four compartments
breached, but not five.
Not five. As she goes down,
the water will spill...
over the tops of the bulkheads
at E deck, one to the next...
back and back. There's no stopping it.
The pumps.
The pumps buy you time, but minutes only.
As of now, no matter what we do...
Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron. I assure you, she can.
And she will.
It's a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour. Two, at most.
How many aboard, Mr. Murdoch?
Two thousand, two hundred souls, sir.
Well, I believe you may get your headlines,
Mr. Ismay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it?
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
- Mr. Hockley?
- Not now. We're busy.
You've been asked to put on lifebelts
and go to the boat deck.
I said, not now.
I'm sorry, Mr. Hockley, but it's
Captain's orders. Dress warmly.
It's quite cold out.
May I suggest topcoats and hats?
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss.
I'm sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up! Lifebelts on!
What's he on about?
- Put your lifebelts on!
- What is it?
Just put them on.
C.Q. D?
Sir?
That's right, C.Q.D. The distress call.
That's our position.
Tell whoever responds we're going down
and need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
Steady! Make it taut! And winch out!
Uncover this boat! Uncover
all the boats aft!
Release those ties!
Roll back that cover! Smartly now!
Where are the passengers?
They went inside. Too
cold and noisy for them.
You there! Get down here
and help with these lines!
Care for a drink, sir?
Sonny, what's doing? You get us all trussed
up and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am. Let me go find out.
Nobody knows what's going on.
Just like the damn English...
everything by the book.
No need for language, Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn on the heaters in our rooms.
I want a cup of tea when I return.
Mr. Andrews.
I saw the iceberg. And
I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
You're certain?
In an hour or so, all this
will be at the bottom of the Atlantic.
Please, tell only who you must.
I don't want to cause a panic.
And get to a boat. Quickly. Don't wait.
You remember what I told
you about the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Over here, son.
Sir, there's a big mob
at the Second Class Purser's office.
Go on. I'll watch him.
Aye. Right.
Sir, Carpathia says they're making 17 knots.
Full steam for them, sir.
She's the only one responding?
The only one close. They'll
be here in four hours.
Four hours?!
Thank you, Bride.
My God.
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women and children
into the boats?
Yes.
Women and children first, yes.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen, attention, please!
Step this way, please. That's right.
Come towards me. Thank you.
Good.
For the time being,
I require only women and children.
Right here.
Like the Captain said,
nice and cheery, so there's no panic.
"Wedding Dance."
Lifebelts on. Put your lifebelts on.
Put your lifebelts on. Lifebelt on.
Here, put that lifebelt on. Turn it around.
It isn't time to go to the boats yet!
Please, stay calm.
Make sure you have your lifebelts on.
Let women and children
through to the front.
What are we doing?
Waiting. Once first-class people
are in the boats...
they'll start with us
and we want to be ready.
Pushing won't get you out any faster.
Go get help.
Lower it away, left and
right together! Steady.
Both sides together! Steady!
Steady!
Stop, stop, stop!
Hold the left!
Right side only! Right side only!
Right side!
Hold the left! Right side down!
Lower away together!
Steady, lads!
You know, I do believe this ship may sink.
I've been asked to give you
this small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister, you heard
the man. Into the boat.
Any room for a gentleman,
gentlemen?
Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be
seated according to class?
I hope they're not too crowded.
Oh, Mother, shut up!
Don't you understand?
The water is freezing and
there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half.
Half the people on this
ship are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First class seats
are right up here.
You know, it's a pity I didn't
keep that drawing.
It'll be worth a lot
more by morning.
You unimaginable bastard.
Come on, Rose darling.
There's plenty of room for you.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come into the boat, Rose.
Come.
Rose.
Get into the boat!
Good-bye, Mother.
Where are you going?
To him?!
To be a whore to a gutter rat?
I'd rather be his whore
than your wife.
No!
I said, no!
Rose! Please, stop!
And, lower away!
No, Wait!
Lower away!
- Rose!
- Lower together!
Hold the left side!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?!
Hello! Help me!
Help me!
Can you hear me?!
Can anybody hear me?!
Somebody help me!
Mr. Andrews?!
Steward, check the
starboard corridor.
Madame, please put on a lifebelt.
Get to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake put on your
lifebelt and set a good example.
Yes sir.
- Anyone in here?
- Mr. Andrews!
Mr. Andrews! Thank God!
Where would the Master at Arms
take someone under arrest?
What? You have to get
to a boat right away.
No!
I'm doing this with or
without your help, sir.
But without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the
very bottom. Go to the left...
down the crewmen's passage.
Then go right and left
again at the stairs.
You'll come to a long corridor.
This could be bad.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Excuse me. Thank you.
I'm sorry, miss,
but the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite,
goddamnit!
Now take me down!
E deck.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
I'm going back up.
No! No! No!
Come back! I'm going back up!
I'm going back up!
Crew passage.
Jack!
Rose!
Rose, I'm in here!
I'm in here!
Jack! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
That guy Lovejoy put
it in my pocket.
I know, I know, I know.
Listen Rose...
you're gonna have to find
the spare key, all right?
Look in that
cabinet right there.
It's a little silver one, Rose.
These are all brass ones!
Check right here, Rose.
Rose.
How did you find out I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
Keep looking.
No key.
There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen.
You're gonna have
to go find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
I'll just wait here!
Hello? Is there anyone here?
Hello?
Is there anybody down here?
We need help! Hello?
Damnit!
Can anybody hear me, please?!
Hello?! Hello?!
Oh, thank God.
Wait, please, I need your help.
There's a man back
here and he's...
Wait!
Hello?!
Hello?
Miss, you shouldn't
be here now.
I need your help.
There is a man down
here and he is trapped.
- This way, yes. All right.
- Please!
- There's no need to panic.
- No, I'm not panicking!
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me! Listen!!!
To hell with you.
Oh, my God.
Will this work?
I guess we'll find out.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Try a couple practice
swings over there.
Good.
Now try and hit the same mark
again, Rose. You can do it.
Okay, that's enough practice.
Come on, Rose.
You can do it.
Listen, just hit it really hard
and really fast.
Come on. Wait.
Open your
hands up a little more.
- Like that?
- Right.
Listen, Rose, I trust you.
Go.
You did it!
Come on. Let's go.
Oh shit, this is cold!
Oh, shit!
Shit! Shit!
This is the way out.
We have to find
another way. Come on.
Pull.
Put your backs into it.
Pull!
Now, there's something
you don't see every day.
What's this luggage doing here?
Get rid of it. Get rid of it.
We need the room.
Get rid of that. Out.
This way.
Let go, sir. Get back.
Keep calm!
Lovejoy!
She's not on the starboard side either.
We're running out of time. This strutting
martinet isn't letting any men on at all.
There's one on the other
side letting men on.
Well then, that's our play.
We'll need some
insurance first. Come on.
This way, please.
All the way down here.
Here!
What do you think you're doing?
You'll have to pay for
that, you know.
That's White Star
Line property.
Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment?
I just have to run back to my room...
Sit down!
She's the last.
- Prepare to lower.
- Mr. Lightoller.
Why are the boats being
launched half full?
Not now, Mr. Andrews.
There, look. 20 or so
in a boat built for 65?
And I saw one boat
with only 12. 12!
Well, we weren't sure of
the weight, Mr. Andrews.
These boats may buckle.
Rubbish!
They were tested in Belfast
with the weight of 70 men.
Now, fill these boats, Mr. Lightoller.
For God's sake man!
Please, I need more women
and children, please!
Get back in there!
This is not an exit.
You can't keep us locked in here.
Like animals. The ship's bloody sinking.
Bring forward the women!
Unlock the gates.
Women only!
No men!
Get back!
Lock the gates!
Get them back from those gates!
Don't touch the gates!
For God's sake, man...
there are women and
children down here!
Let us up so we can have a chance!
Get back!
Tommy!
- Can we get out?
- It's hopeless that way.
Whatever we do,
we've got to do it fast.
The boats are all going.
This whole place is flooding.
We've gotta get out of here.
There is niente this way.
Let's go this way, all right?
Come on!
I make my own luck.
So do I.
Come on!
No, come on, let's go this way.
This way!
Just go back to
the main stairwell.
And everything will be
sorted out there.
It will all get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
- Open the gate!
- Go back down the main stairwell.
Open the gate right now!
Go back down the main
stairwell, like I told you.
Goddamn it! Son of a bitch!
Stop that!
Fabri, Tommy,
give me a hand here.
Move aside.
Come on, pull!
Pull!
Move aside.
Quickly, move aside!
Put that down!
- Move aside!
- Put that down!
One! Two!
Three!
Again!
Now, let's go!
Let's go, Rose.
You can't go up there!
You can't do this!
Keep order! Keep order here!
Back! Back! Back!
Hold on to her!
Pull her in!
Get back, I say, or I'll...
shoot you all like dogs!
Keep order here!
Keep order, I say.
Mr. Lowe, man this boat.
Right. Is everybody all right?
Nobody panic.
Stay back.
We're too late.
There are more boats down the front.
Stay with this one. Murdoch.
He seems to be quite practical.
Don't lower it!
Cut the falls!
Sit down!
Stay back, you lot!
Just stay back, the
lot of you! Stay back!
It's starting to fall apart.
We don't have much time.
Mr. Murdoch?
Mr. Hockley.
You two, with me, now!
I'm a businessman, as you know...
and I have a business
proposition for you.
Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone!
Colonel, are there
any boats on that side?
No, miss, but there are a couple
of boats all the way forward.
This way, I'll lead you.
What's the use?
Nobody's listening to us anyway.
Well, they don't listen to
us at dinner, either.
Come on, let's play.
Keep us warm.
"Orpheus."
Music to drown by.
Now I know I'm in first class.
- Where is everyone?
- They're all still aft, sir.
We have an understanding
then, Mr. Murdoch.
Will the men please hold
back! Hold back, I say!
Women and children only!
Get back!
Come through, madame.
This way. Step back, sir!
You better check the
other side. Go!
I found her, on the other side.
Waiting for a boat.
With him.
- Any more women and children?
- They're all aboard, Mr. Murdoch.
Anyone else then?
- Anyone else?
- Do hurry. Hurry along.
Goddamn it all to hell.
Shit.
Fire!
Sir, sir, you can't
go through here.
That's it. Splendid. Right.
Prepare to lower.
Ready on the left.
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together.
Steady. Keep it steady.
- Give her to me.
- Daddy.
It'll be fine, darling.
Don't you worry.
Daddy, get in the boat.
It's good-bye for a little
while. Only for a little while.
There'll be another
boat for the daddies.
This boat is for the
mummies and the children.
You hold Mummy's hand
and be a good little girl.
I'm not going without you.
No, you have to go, now.
No, Jack.
Get in the boat, Rose.
Yes.
Get on the boat!
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
Oh my God, look at you.
You look a fright.
Here.
Put this on. Come.
Go on. I'll get the next one.
No, not without you.
I'll be all right.
Listen, I'll be fine.
I'm a survivor, all right?
Don't worry about me.
Now, go on. Get on.
I have an arrangement with an
officer on the other side of the ship.
Jack and I can get off safely.
Both of us.
See?
I got my own boat to catch.
Go on, hurry.
They're almost full.
- Step aboard, miss.
- Go. Go.
Step aboard, please.
You're daddy's
good girl, all right?
You're my little sailor.
Clear the rail, please.
And, lower away!
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
There's no... there's no
arrangement, is there?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
I always win, Jack.
One way or another.
Rose!
Stop her!
Rose, what are you doing?!
No!
Rose! You're so stupid!
Why did you do that?
You're so stupid, Rose.
Why did you do that? Why?!
You jump, I jump, right?
Right.
Oh God. I couldn't go.
I couldn't go, Jack.
It's all right. We'll
think of something.
- At least I'm with you.
- We'll think of something.
Come on! Move!
Come on! Move.
Come on!
Move!
Come on! Come on Rose.
Rose, come on!
Move Rose!
Go!
I hope you enjoy your time together!
What could possibly be funny?
I put the diamond in the coat.
And I put the coat on her!
Come on!
Dada!
We can't leave him.
All right, come on!
Dada!
Go back!
It's the wrong way! Come back!
No, not that way!
Come back! Stop!
Go!
Go! Run!
This way!
Give me your hand!
Oh, God!
Help!
Wait, sir!
Sir, open the gate, please!
Help us, please!
Help us!
- Please!
Bloody hell!
- Come on, come on!
- Come on!
Go, go!
Jesus.
- Please!
- Come on!
Hurry!
Come on!
I'm sorry, I dropped the keys.
- Wait, please!
- Wait!
Don't leave! Please,
send for help!
I got it! Which
one is it, Rose?
The short one.
Try the short one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh no! It won't go in.
It's stuck! It's stuck!
- Come on!
- Hurry, Jack!
I got it! I got it!
Go! Go, Rose!
Go! Go!
Jack! Come on!
Move, move.
- Get those oars in place.
- Get an oar under it.
Hold it! Hold it!
Hold it!
Get these davits cranked in!
Let's get the falls hooked up!
Mommy!
Keep going up!
Stop pushing!
Stay back!
Will you give us a chance
to live, you limey bastard!
I'll shoot any man who tries
to get past me! Get back!
Bastard!
Get back!
We had a deal, damn you!
Your money can't save you
any more than it could save me.
Get back!
Women and children only!
No, Tommy!
No, Will!
Now stand back, damn you!
Gently, gently. Hold it. Hold it.
I have a child!
- I have a child!
- Clear a path here!
Please, I have a child!
Please. I'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back!
- Please?
- Here, give her to me.
You're all right, dearie.
Give her here.
There, there.
Wait, wait, wait! Mr. Andrews!
Oh, Rose.
Won't you even
make a try for it?
I'm sorry that I didn't build you
a stronger ship, young Rose.
It's going fast.
We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr. Guggenheim?
These are for you, Mr. Guggenheim.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best and are
prepared to go down as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
Get the falls over here now!
Let them drop. Then we'll right it.
Capitán?
Capitán, where should I go? Please.
Captain. Captain. Sir.
Right. That's it, then.
Good-bye, Wally. Good luck.
- Good-bye, Wallace.
- So long, old chap.
And so they lived happily
together for 300 years...
in the land of Tir na nog...
Land of eternal
youth and beauty.
There's no time!
Cut those falls!
Cut them!
Cut them if you have to!
I need a knife!
Cut the falls now!
Cut them loose!
Cut those bloody falls!
Gentlemen...
it has been a privilege
playing with you tonight.
We have to stay on the
ship as long as possible.
Come on!
This way. Through the rail.
Come on, Rose.
Jump.
Come on.
I got you. Jump.
I've got you, miss.
Back!
No! You'll swamp us!
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death...
You wanna walk a little faster
through that valley there?
Holy Mary, mother of God...
pray for us sinners now and
at the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
This way.
Come on!
And I saw a new heaven
and a new earth...
for the first heaven and the first earth
had passed away...
and there was no more sea.
It'll be over soon.
It'll all be over soon.
And He shall dwell with them.
And they shall be His people
and God Himself shall be with them...
and be their God.
Jack...
this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away
all the tears from their eyes...
and there shall be
no more death.
Neither shall there be
sorrow or crying.
Neither shall there
be any more pain...
for the former world
has passed away.
Bloody pull faster! And pull!
Hang on, miss Trudy!
Hold on real tight.
God Almighty.
Keep those breakers in!
Keep them in!
We have to move!
Give me your hand.
I'll pull you over.
I can't.
Come on!
Give me your hand.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Come on, I've got you.
- What's happening, Jack?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Hold on.
This is it!
Oh, my God, Jack!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Hold on!
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when I say.
Kick for the surface
and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're going to make it, Rose.
Trust me.
I trust you.
Ready! Ready!
Now!
Jack! Jack!
Rose!
Get off her! Get off her!
Swim, Rose! I need you to swim!
Keep swimming.
It's so cold.
Swim, Rose!
Come on.
Keep swimming.
Here...
get on it.
Get on top.
Come on, Rose.
Stay on it. Stay on, Rose.
It'll be all right now.
Return...
the boats!
The boats are coming
back for us Rose.
Hold on just a
little bit longer.
They had to row
away for the suction...
but now they'll be coming back.
For God's sake!
Please...
help us!
You don't understand.
If we go back, they'll
swamp the boat.
They'll pull us right down,
I'm telling you.
Oh, knock it off.
You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab
an oar. Let's go.
Are you out of your mind?
We're in the middle of the North Atlantic.
Now, do you people want to live
or do you want to die?!
I don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you?
It's your men out there!
There's plenty of room for more.
And there'll be one less
on this boat...
if you don't shut that
hole in your face!
Now, bring in your oars over there.
And tie these boats together as well.
Now, make sure that's
tied up nice and tight.
Right, listen to me, men.
We have to go back.
I want to transfer all the women
from this boat into that boat right now...
as quick as you can, please.
Let's create some space over there.
Move forward and aft.
It's getting quiet.
It's just going to take a
couple of minutes...
to get the boats organized.
I don't know about you but...
I intend to write
a strongly worded letter...
to the White Star Line
about all this.
I love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your
good-byes. Not yet.
Do you understand me?
I'm so cold.
Listen, Rose...
you're gonna get out of here.
You're gonna go on...
and you're gonna
make lots of babies.
And you're gonna
watch them grow.
You're gonna die an old...
an old lady.
Warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night. Not like this.
Do you understand me?
I can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket, Rose...
was the best thing that
ever happened to me.
It brought me to you.
And I'm thankful
for that, Rose.
I'm thankful.
You must...
you must do me this honor.
You must promise me
that you'll survive.
That you won't give up...
no matter what happens.
No matter how hopeless.
Promise me now, Rose.
And never let go
of that promise.
I promise.
Never let go.
I'll never let go, Jack.
I'll never let go.
Right ahead, sir.
Oars!
Do you see any moving?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them. Make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now, give way.
Ahead easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
Is there anyone
alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
Is there anyone
alive out there?
We waited too long.
Well, keep checking them!
Keep looking!
Is there anyone
alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
Come, Josephine...
in my flying machine
And it's up she goes
Up she goes
Come, Josephine...
in my flying...
Jack.
There's a boat.
There's a boat, Jack.
Come back.
Come back. Come back!
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back.
I'll never let go.
I promise.
Come about!
Fifteen hundred people
went into the sea...
when Titanic
sank from under us.
There were twenty
boats floating nearby...
and only one came back.
One.
Six were saved
from the water...
myself included.
Six...
out of fifteen hundred.
Afterward...
the seven hundred
people in the boats...
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die.
Wait to live.
Wait for an absolution...
that would never come.
Sir, I don't think you'll find any
of your people down here.
It's all steerage.
His hair is reddish brown,
reddish brown, reddish brown.
White beard.
Isn't there another
passenger list?
There is no other list.
Perhaps he's on another ship.
We're doing all we can,
ma'am. I'm so sorry.
That's the last time
I ever saw him.
He married. Of course.
And inherited his millions.
But the Crash of '29 hit
his interests hard...
and he put a pistol in
his mouth that year.
Or so I read.
Can I take your name
please, love?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found
anything on Jack.
There's no record
of him at all.
No, there wouldn't
be, would there?
And I've never spoken
of him until now.
Not to anyone.
Not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart is a
deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was
a man named Jack Dawson...
and that he saved me...
in every way that
a person can be saved.
I don't even have
a picture of him.
He exists now only
in my memory.
Keldysh, Mir 2 on our
way to the surface.
I was saving this for when
I found the diamond.
I'm sorry.
Three years...
I've thought of
nothing except Titanic.
But I never got it.
I never let it in.